<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Tyler Tate</title>
		<description>Making the complex feel simple.</description>
		<link>http://www.tylertate.com/</link>
		<atom:link href="http://tylertate.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
			<item>
				<title>The Discovery Gap</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/07/12/the-discovery-gap.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/07/12/the-discovery-gap.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Personalized Recommendations: Coffees Tailored to You</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/28/personalized-recommendations-coffees-tailored-to-you.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/28/personalized-recommendations-coffees-tailored-to-you.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Brew Log: Your Coffee Palate, Visualized</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/21/brew-log-your-coffee-palate-visualized.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/21/brew-log-your-coffee-palate-visualized.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Ratings: Remember the Coffees You Love</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/14/ratings-remember-coffees-you-love.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/06/14/ratings-remember-coffees-you-love.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>2016 Coffee Trends</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/04/15/2016-coffee-trends.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/04/15/2016-coffee-trends.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>What Peet’s acquisition of Stumptown and Intelligentsia says about the state of coffee</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/04/07/peets-acquisition-stumptown-intelligentsia-state-of-coffee.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2016/04/07/peets-acquisition-stumptown-intelligentsia-state-of-coffee.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Introducing Crema.co 1.0</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/12/04/introducing-crema-1.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/12/04/introducing-crema-1.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Feature: Happier Email</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/10/05/new-feature-happier-email.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/10/05/new-feature-happier-email.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Naming Startups</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The venerable &lt;a href=&quot;http://paulgraham.com/name.html&quot;&gt;Paul Graham&lt;/a&gt; postulated in a blog post recently:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If you have a US startup called X and you don’t have x.com, you should probably change your name.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an oversimplification. Whether a domain ends in .com is just one of several important characteristics to consider in naming a startup. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;When&lt;/em&gt; (and when not to) splurge on a .com is the more fundamental question&lt;/strong&gt; (hint: skip to the end for the answer, or stick around for my story).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever named a company, I’m sure you can testify that it takes research, imagination, and an open mind. I recently went on that journey myself, and learned several things along the way: like some of the criteria to consider, how to use those criteria to effectively evaluate names, and when it’s worth going .com. Here’s how the story unfolded for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;naming-cremaco&quot;&gt;Naming Crema.co&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around this time last year I was in the early process of conceptualizing and naming &lt;a href=&quot;http://crema.co/&quot;&gt;Crema.co&lt;/a&gt;, a coffee marketplace with a Netflix queue-like subscription model. I’ve been complicit in choosing names for a few companies over the years, but this was my first time naming an online consumer brand. Not only did the name itself need to be meaningful, but the &lt;em&gt;domain name&lt;/em&gt; had to be short, memorable, and affordable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, I spent &lt;em&gt;months&lt;/em&gt; trying to come up with the perfect name. I had brainstormed well over 300 (mostly bad) ideas, made around 100 enquiries with existing domain name owners, and had a “shortlist” 50 entries long. Every car trip I coerced my wife into helping me come up with ideas. I accosted friends and family to run names by then. In a word: I was obsessed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first names that I thought of were boringly straightforward. Because of this, they were also unaffordable (everyone else had thought of them too). The subsequent waves of names relied on misspellings, made-up words, and non-dot-com extensions to try to arrive at something attainable. This is where the real creative challenge lies. (Daniel Eckler’s post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.growth.supply/how-to-name-a-unicorn-what-you-need-to-know-about-naming-a-billion-dollar-startup-e52b12cd7f77&quot;&gt;How to Name a Unicorn&lt;/a&gt;, shares some great tips on the art of brainstorming.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, there was a name that led the pack at any given time. Some of the leaders held their position for weeks. But uncertainty would creep back in, and the search would resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-in-a-name&quot;&gt;What’s in a name?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turning point in my quest came when I began writing down the characteristics I was looking for in a name. It sounds obvious, but while I had inklings of these qualities from the beginning, putting them down on paper helped me to evaluate each name more objectively, and helped circumvent emotional attachment to weaker names. For me, the criteria clustered around three categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meaning&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Memorability&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cost&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meaning&lt;/em&gt; tends to be what drives ideation, while &lt;em&gt;memorability&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;cost&lt;/em&gt; are funnels that filter out most of the possibilities that come out of brainstorming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within each of these categories, I articulated specific qualities that I was looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meaning&quot;&gt;Meaning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a name synonymous with coffee that would connote hand-crafted quality, and perhaps also be extendable to other food and beverage categories. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On encountering the name for the first time, would someone have a clue that it’s a marketplace for buying coffee?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On encountering the name for the first time, would someone have a clue that it is an online marketplace for other foods and beverages?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does it convey coffee/food/beverages hand-produced by expert craftsmen/craftswomen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;memorability&quot;&gt;Memorability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because I was building an online consumer marketplace, I needed a name that was short and phonetic; something people could easily remember and spell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you know how to spell it if you first heard it in conversation?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it short in length (&amp;lt;5 characters), medium length (6-7 characters), or long (8+ characters)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Would you remember the name (including its spelling) if you had seen it once before?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it hip and offbeat rather than boringly direct?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cost&quot;&gt;Cost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, I needed a name that I could afford. This is where .coms are problematic. My bootstrapped budget for a domain was $10,000 (and preferably much less). While it would obviously be great if I could find a strong .com for that amount, I was happy enough if the equivalent .com was attainable for $50,000 or less; I could always buy it later once the company takes off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it doable ($5-10k), affordable ($1-4.9k), or virtually free (&amp;lt;$1k)?	&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is it a .com? If not, could the .com be attainable later for 50k or less?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evaluate&quot;&gt;Evaluate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I had formalized these criteria, I ended up &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/crema.co/spreadsheets/d/1dP-i-gWNh7yyJemKN6-PjdsXZbu_h0-_mz4XJmWa_ek/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;throwing them into a spreadsheet&lt;/a&gt; so I could compare my name candidates side by side. To keep things simple, I decided to give each name a thumbs down (0), neutral (1), or thumbs up (2) for each criterion. I then tallied up the subtotals for meaning, memorability, cost (points awarded / total possible points), and averaged the three subtotals together to arrive at the final score, expressed as a percentage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/crema.co/spreadsheets/d/1dP-i-gWNh7yyJemKN6-PjdsXZbu_h0-_mz4XJmWa_ek/edit?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2015-09-08/spreadsheet.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;My spreadsheet for evaluating startup names. (You&#39;re welcome to use it as a starting point.)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point it’s important to keep in mind that anytime a quantitative system is used to evaluate subjective qualities, the results should be interpreted with several grains of salt. This model assumes I’ve identified all the right criteria, evaluated each name objectively, and weighted the scores proportionally, none of which are completely true. In leu of perfection, the smell test will have to suffice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, Crema.co scored the highest of the 10 names I evaluated using the spreadsheet, with a total score of 81%. Before doing the analysis, I had favored Crave.co and Stache.co, which both scored around 50% by comparison. And earlier I’d been irrationally attached to Yarn.co, which garnered a dire 21% in the analysis. Had I not gone through this exercise, I may have opted for an inferior name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;to-com-or-not-to-com&quot;&gt;To .com, or not to .com?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, back to the opening question: should startups opt for a .com, as Paul Graham suggests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graham rightly points out that having a .com signals strength. This is undeniably true; almost all highly successful online companies now have a short .com domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key word being &lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.johnfdoherty.com/startup-brand/&quot;&gt;John Doherty&lt;/a&gt; recently wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What Graham failed to mention is that 4 of the top 8 [YCombinator companies] started with a different domain name than what they ended up with.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dropbox started with getdropbox.com. Stripe was getstripe.com. Airbnb was airbedandbreakfast.com. Facebook started as thefacebook.com. And more recently, plenty of other companies have started with .co and .io domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick with .coms is that they’re expensive. It’s extremely unlikely that you’ll find a suitable .com that hasn’t already been registered, which means you have to buy it on the secondary market. And to put cost in context, the current owner of crema.com is asking six figures. (Morgan Linton’s post &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/life-learning/what-every-startup-founder-should-know-about-buying-domain-names-a6f04357b135&quot;&gt;What Every Startup Founder Should Know About Buying Domain Names&lt;/a&gt; provides a healthy dose of realism.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-1-rule&quot;&gt;The 1% rule&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real question is not, “Should you go .com?”, but rather, “How much should you spend to get a strong domain?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to suggest a rule of thumb:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t spend more than 1% of your company’s valuation on a domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you’re a new startup and you’ve raised $100,000 in seed funding at a $1,000,000 valuation. It would be foolish to blow half of your capital on a $50,000 domain name. At that point in the company’s life, whether the name ends in .com will have almost no impact on whether or not you’ll make it to the next stage. Cutting your runway in half by waving goodbye to $50,000 (and 5% of your company), however, &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; have a trememdous impact. In this circumstance, $10,000 is the maximum you should consider spending — 1% of the company’s $1 million valuation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If, on the other hand, you’ve built a successful company and just raised a $2 million round at a $10 million valuation to accelerate growth, it might be time to spring for that short and sweet .com for as much as $100,000 (again, no more than 1% of the company’s valuation).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules of thumb are, by definition, sweeping generalizations. A short .com deliveres less value to a B2B company than to a consumer brand, for example, so B2Bs should probably spend less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The main point is to think about domain name purchases in terms of your current valuation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-back&quot;&gt;Looking back&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In naming &lt;a href=&quot;http://crema.co/&quot;&gt;Crema.co&lt;/a&gt;, the biggest thing I learned was the importance of defining the characteristics I was looking for in a name. Getting those out of my head, onto paper — and in my case, into a spreadsheet — helped me overcome irrational emotional attachments and think more objectively about each potential name. And, contrary to Paul Graham’s advice, I’m content with a non-dot-com. For now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/10/01/naming-startups-choosing-a-company-name.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/10/01/naming-startups-choosing-a-company-name.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Feature: Order History</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/09/16/new-feature-order-history.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/09/16/new-feature-order-history.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>New Feature: Pause Your Brewlist</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/09/01/new-feature-pause-your-brewlist.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/09/01/new-feature-pause-your-brewlist.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A few things we’ve learned from our Kickstarter backers</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/07/31/a-few-things-weve-learned-from-our-kickstarter-backers.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/07/31/a-few-things-weve-learned-from-our-kickstarter-backers.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Introducing the PourPod: A Single-Serve Pod for Pour-Over Coffee</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/04/01/introducing-the-pourpod.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/04/01/introducing-the-pourpod.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designers as Innovators, and a Story About Coffee</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Designers are problem solvers. They ask the question: “How can we make it easier and more enjoyable for people to achieve their goals?” They create prototypes, put them in front of users, and then iterate their design solutions until the experience matches the user’s needs and wants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, designers are employed to create a new mobile application or make an existing website easier to use. But design thinking is also well suited for another, broader purpose: disruptive innovation. The ethos that makes designers effective at crafting experiences also equips them to become innovators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same approach, techniques, and values that make designers effective at crafting usable, enjoyable experiences—what we could call “design thinking”—also positions them to become innovators and entrepreneurs. To make the leap from designer to innovator, we simply need to think bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What follows are personal observations I’ve made over the last four months as a designer turned founder of Crema.co, an online marketplace for single-origin coffee. I’ve noticed four design practices that, when broadened, are crucial to successful innovation: identifying a problem, formulating a solution, talking to customers, and iterating.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/04/01/designers-as-innovators.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/04/01/designers-as-innovators.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Starbucks Reserve Roastery Joins the Coffee Subscription Race</title>
				<pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2015 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Amidst the #racetogether controversy last week, Starbucks customers received an email promoting the company’s latest offering from their Reserve Roastery: a premium coffee subscription. For $24 a month, customers can become the proud recipient of an 8.8oz bag of small-lot coffee, delivered to their door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Announced earlier this year, the Reserve Roastery and Tasting Room is a move upmarket for Starbucks. Described on the their website as a “one-of-a kind coffee shrine,” the flagship Seattle store integrates immaculate roasting paraphernalia into a cafe experience. Patrons choose from a menu of single-origin coffees that have just been roasted on site, such as the Peru Amazonas from a farming co-op deep in the Amazon rainforest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reserve Roastery coffee subscription offers customers across the country access to the premium coffees sold at the Seattle shop. But this time around, the company that hooked Americans on $4 cappuccinos is playing catchup. Independent specialty roasters such as Intelligentsia, Counter Culture, and Stumptown have long been respected for their small-lot, single-origin coffee. And Blue Bottle, meanwhile, has been the leader in coffee subscriptions since it acquired the ecommerce-savvy Tonx about a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond Blue Bottle, there have been a host of upstarts who have emerged to curate coffee subscriptions of all shapes and sizes. Craft Coffee and Mistobox will choose bags of coffee for you according to your preferences. Angels’ Cup will send you blind samples for you to taste test. And Bean Box will curate an assortment of coffees sourced solely from Seattle-based roasters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newest entrant to the coffee subscription scene, however, offers an alternative to the choiceless ‘curated-for-you’ approach. Crema.co lets customers pick out the coffees they’d like to try for themselves, and add them to a personal “brewlist.” They then set a delivery frequency, and receive the next coffee on their list each time, like a Netflix queue for coffee (disclosure: I’m the company’s founder). Crema.co is also unique in that customers are able to buy coffee directly from their choice of independent roasters, rather than being locked-in to products from a single roaster, such as Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such growing interest in both premium coffee and subscription services, the Starbucks Reserve Roastery coffee subscription is an obvious, if overdue, move for the company. But will customers be willing to swallow the $24 price tag?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you tried an online coffee subscription before? What was your experience?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/03/28/starbucks-reserve-roastery-joins-the-coffee-subscription-race.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/03/28/starbucks-reserve-roastery-joins-the-coffee-subscription-race.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Back Us on Kickstarter</title>
				<pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/03/08/back-us-on-kickstarter.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/03/08/back-us-on-kickstarter.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Hello World, Meet Crema</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/01/27/hello-world-meet-crema.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/01/27/hello-world-meet-crema.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Case for a Coffee Marketplace</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A tiny, four-wheel drive Geo Tracker trudges up a steep, narrow dirt path, delicately hugging the side of a mountain some 100 kilometers from San Jose, Costa Rica. After a particularly hair-pin turn, the Tracker bravely sprints up an intense incline, but is met halfway up with an aging Toyota pickup half creeping, half sliding down the hill. Only after an involved series of maneuvers — comparable to trapeze stunts in both complexity and risk of tumbling to a tragic death — do the two vehicles manage to pass, and we’re able to continue our treacherous journey to Henry’s coffee farm further up the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was 2006. It was the summer before my last year of university, and I was spending four weeks working with an upstart coffee roaster in Costa Rica called Green Earth Coffee. Their goal: to provide consumers with exceptional coffee, while providing local farmers and agricultural workers  higher wages and better access to medical care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small left&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: 0.75em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2015-01-16/window.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The valley below. Or: where we would have ended up if our left wheels had been an inch or two closer to the edge of the &quot;road&quot;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2015-01-16/tracker.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;In a Geo Tracker on the side of a mountain, somewhere near Los Sabos, Costa Rica.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-thousand-faces&quot;&gt;A thousand faces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Earth Coffee’s story isn’t particularly unique. There are thousands of independent coffee roasters in the United States alone. Many of them are dedicated to making coffee an exceptional, ethical, and sustainable trade. And likewise, more and more consumers are drawn to artisanal, socially responsible brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet there are difficulties. Consumers have poor access to these upstanding coffee producers, and so are obliged settle for whatever is stocked on the supermarket shelf. Boutique coffee roasters, meanwhile, find it difficult to reach retail consumers, with most of their business coming from wholesale sales to coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An online marketplace that connects consumers directly with specialty roasters and, by extension, coffee growers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/08/from-famine-to-feast-foods-online-future.html&quot;&gt;From Famine to Feast: Food’s Online Future&lt;/a&gt;, I argued that online channels are poised to disrupt the way that way people shop for groceries. While in &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/09/online-grocery-shopping-a-hard-nut-to-crack.html&quot;&gt;Online Grocery Shopping: A Hard Nut to Crack&lt;/a&gt;, I outlined three obstacles to buying food and beverages online, and strategies for overcoming them. I believe that coffee is an ideal catalyst for brining about such a change. In addition to bridging the gap between producer and consumer, a coffee marketplace is buttressed by two underlying trends: changing consumer attitudes, and a significant and growing market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;changing-consumer-attitudes&quot;&gt;Changing consumer attitudes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While 61% of American adults drink coffee every day, what’s more impressive is that over half of them have switched to what the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncausa.org/custom/headlines/headlinedetails.cfm?id=897&amp;amp;returnto=778&quot;&gt;National Coffee Association&lt;/a&gt; defines as “specialty” coffee. What’s even more impressive, however, is that 42% of millennials (or, more precisely, those aged 25-39) drink specialty coffee &lt;strong&gt;every day&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s 26 million people in the United States alone — equivalent to the entire population of Australia. And, as I &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/08/from-famine-to-feast-foods-online-future.html&quot;&gt;pointed out previously&lt;/a&gt;, it’s also the same age group most likely to buy online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;26 million millennials drink gourmet coffee every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-significant-and-growing-market&quot;&gt;A significant and growing market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans were projected to spend over $48 billion on coffee in 2014, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://finance.yahoo.com/news/coffee-ready-drink-coffee-u-225500585.html&quot;&gt;Reportlinker.com&lt;/a&gt;. Three quarters of that was spent at coffee shops and restaurants, but a significant $11.2 billion was spent at retailers (such as grocery stores) on coffee for brewing at home. Of that amount, around $5 billion was spent on &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scaa.org/PDF/resources/facts-and-figures.pdf&quot;&gt;specialty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; coffee specifically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Americans spend $5 Billion on gourmet coffee to brew at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;case-closed&quot;&gt;Case closed?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that there are a lot of people spending a lot of money on a lot of specialty coffee. And while consumer attitudes are shifting towards artisanal, socially responsible coffees, there remains significant friction separating conscientious consumers from small, boutique roasters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is about to change.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/01/16/the-case-for-a-coffee-marketplace.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2015/01/16/the-case-for-a-coffee-marketplace.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Online Grocery Shopping: A Hard Nut to Crack</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2014 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: -1.43em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/hypermarket.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Packaged food aisles at a Fred Meyer hypermarket in Portland, Oregon.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my previous post, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/08/from-famine-to-feast-foods-online-future.html&quot;&gt;From Famine to Feast: Food’s Online Future&lt;/a&gt;,” I outlined three reasons that I believe the food industry is poised for a profound transformation as consumers shift from brick-and-mortar to online channels. This, however, begs the question:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Why hasn’t online food shopping already taken off in the United States?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we already buy so many other things online — from books to electronics to made-by-hand knickknacks — why not food? Does the inherent nature of food make it unsuitable for online commerce?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, to look beyond the US, online grocery shopping is already a “thing”. In the United Kingdom, for instance, online-only retailers such as Ocado, as well as major supermarket chains like Tesco, provide polished online grocery shopping and delivery services, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igd.com/our-expertise/Retail/retail-outlook/3371/UK-Grocery-Retailing/&quot;&gt;statistics show&lt;/a&gt; that 4.4% of all grocery sales occurred online in 2014, some £7.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-reasons-for-failure&quot;&gt;Three reasons for failure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UK aside, I think there are three reasons why online grocery shopping has proven to be a hard nut to crack in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/icon-warehouse.svg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;warehousing-cost&quot;&gt;1. Warehousing Cost&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To fulfil a customer’s order, the business must have a warehouse located nearby. In a country as large as the US, this would require an immense amount of capital to achieve nationally, and is why new services such as Google Shopping and Amazon Fresh are currently offered in just a handful of cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/icon-truck.svg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;delivery-complexity&quot;&gt;2. Delivery Complexity&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not only must the business operate a local warehouse, but they must also maintain a fleet of refrigerated trucks to keep perishable goods cool, and freezer goods frozen during transit. This adds yet another layer of both logistical complexity and capital intensity that must be rolled out across a vast geography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/icon-cheap.svg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unprofitable-goods&quot;&gt;3. Unprofitable Goods&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many grocery items are inexpensive, heavy, perishable, or some combination of the above. By the time a $1 bag of sugar is stored in the warehouse, loaded on the truck, and driven to the customer’s home, for instance, it has probably cost the business well above $1 in logistical expense. It’s hard to turn a profit on such inexpensive foodstuffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small right&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/webvan.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-lesson-from-the-past&quot;&gt;A lesson from the past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three challenges were personified — even caricatured — in the textbook failure of Webvan, what &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/09/27/why-webvan-failed-and-how-home-delivery-2-0-is-addressing-the-problems/&quot;&gt;Peter Relan&lt;/a&gt; calls “the poster child of the dot-com bubble.” Started in 1998, Webvan raised $800 million from investors to become an online grocery store providing home delivery. They devised state-of-the-art warehousing systems, secured fleets of refrigerated trucks, and committed $1 billion of capital to build warehouses across 26 cities. In 2001, Webvan filed for bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;present-attempts&quot;&gt;Present attempts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s businesses are loath to repeat the mistakes of Webvan. Of current ventures, only Amazon Fresh and east coast startup Relay Foods are attempting a Webvan-style warehousing and delivery approach. A number of others, including Google Shopping, Instacart, and Postmates, are aiming to provide the &lt;strong&gt;delivery service without the warehousing&lt;/strong&gt;. That is, they will go to the local supermarket for you, and bring the goods to your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see three flaws to such an approach:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using a third-party delivery service will always add an &lt;strong&gt;additional layer of price markup&lt;/strong&gt;. That is, since the third-party is not profiting from the sale of an item, they will have to add their own fees on top of the store’s retail price.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brick-and-mortar retailers could easily launch their own delivery services. By doing so, they could either &lt;strong&gt;block the third parties&lt;/strong&gt; from accessing their stores outright, or just &lt;strong&gt;underprice&lt;/strong&gt; the third-party services (which they would have the capacity to do since they are already profiting from buying wholesale and selling retail).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third-party delivery services are &lt;strong&gt;limited to the selection&lt;/strong&gt; provided by local stores. Online retailers, by contrast, are often able to provide a much wider selection than their brick-and-mortar counterparts (think Amazon.com vs. a local bookstore), an advantage that third-party delivery services lack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is another way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-09/cupcake.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-recipe-for-the-future&quot;&gt;A recipe for the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that the future of online food shopping is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;be-the-marketplace-not-warehouse&quot;&gt;1. Be the marketplace, not warehouse&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warehousing is expensive, difficult, and tends to limit selection. Instead of being the warehouse, be the marketplace instead. &lt;strong&gt;Enable producers to list their food goods on the online marketplace, and enable customers to buy goods directly from producers.&lt;/strong&gt; It’s relational… just like food used to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outsource-delivery&quot;&gt;2. Outsource delivery&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are existing logistic providers which do nothing but logistics and are really good at it, like the United States Postal Service and FedEx. &lt;strong&gt;Leverage those existing networks&lt;/strong&gt; rather than rolling your own… it’s worked for Amazon.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;go-gourmet&quot;&gt;3. Go gourmet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t sell $1 bags of sugar. Instead, focus on specialty foods that are hard to find at the local grocery store. &lt;strong&gt;Differentiate on quality and selection&lt;/strong&gt;, not on price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-better-world&quot;&gt;A better world?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A marketplace that connects consumers with producers, leverages existing logistics networks, and focuses on specialty food items. I believe this would make the world a happier place…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A place where people are able to discover, buy, and enjoy delicious food that has been lovingly crafted by small, artisanal producers — all more easily than shopping at Wal-Mart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would you like to live in such a world?&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/09/online-grocery-shopping-a-hard-nut-to-crack.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/09/online-grocery-shopping-a-hard-nut-to-crack.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Famine to Feast: Food’s Online Future</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: -1.43em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-08/borough-market.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A cake stall at Borough Market in London. Photo by David Iliff.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Online commerce is a mature, saturated market with little room for new entrants… Or is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cursory glance seems to side with the status quo: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2014/12/02/cyber-monday-record_n_6259082.html&quot;&gt;Cyber Monday&lt;/a&gt; in the United States raked in a whopping $2 billion for online retailers; nearly as many books are sold &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitalbookworld.com/2013/online-retail-now-accounts-for-nearly-half-all-u-s-book-sales/&quot;&gt;electronically&lt;/a&gt; as at brick and mortar stores; and established giants like Amazon seem &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/jeffbercovici/2014/02/10/amazon-vs-book-publishers-by-the-numbers/&quot;&gt;impenetrable&lt;/a&gt;. Surely ecommerce is best left alone, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Not so fast.&lt;/em&gt; While online retailers have a large market share in certain product categories like books, electronics, and sporting goods, other categories remain infantile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the most underdeveloped of segments: &lt;strong&gt;food and drink&lt;/strong&gt;. Americans spend six times more money on groceries than they do on books, but some 40 times more books are purchased online than food and beverages (as a proportion of total sales). This is a &lt;strong&gt;huge, virtually untapped market&lt;/strong&gt;. What’s more, &lt;strong&gt;widespread experimentation&lt;/strong&gt; is underway as tech giants, supermarket chains, and startups try to figure out how to conquer this space. And lastly, a &lt;strong&gt;new generation&lt;/strong&gt; of specialty-food-buying, online-shopping millennials is coming of age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Together, I believe these three elements set the stage for a profound transformation of the food industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-huge-untapped-market&quot;&gt;A huge, untapped market&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013, the grocery bill in the United States totalled around &lt;strong&gt;$1 trillion&lt;/strong&gt; according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.plunkettresearch.com/food-beverage-grocery-market-research/industry-and-business-data&quot;&gt;Plunkett Research&lt;/a&gt;. The average household spent $3,921 on goods to eat and drink at home, the biggest household expenditure after housing and transportation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But though consumers spend a lot on food and drink, they don’t spend that money online. While 38% of media and sporting goods are purchased online, &lt;a href=&quot;https://intelligence.businessinsider.com/this-is-how-much-e-commerce-is-disrupting-the-different-retail-categories-2014-5&quot;&gt;Business Insider&lt;/a&gt; found that…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Less than 1% of food and beverage sales occurred online in 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a massive gap, and one that analysts think will rapidly narrow. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.brickmeetsclick.com/stuff/contentmgr/files/.../pdf/bmc_online_grocery_forecast_10_8_final.pdf&quot;&gt;Brick Meets Click&lt;/a&gt;, for example, predicts that online grocery sales will &lt;strong&gt;rise to 11%-17&lt;/strong&gt;% of the total by 2023, increasing from less than $1 billion today to between $80 and $123 billion. (And it’s worth noting that in other markets such as the United Kingdom, online grocery shopping is already a more substantial 4.4% of the total, according to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.igd.com/our-expertise/Retail/retail-outlook/3371/UK-Grocery-Retailing/&quot;&gt;IDG&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-08/online-spending-graph.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Percentage of online sales by category. Data from Business Insider.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;widespread-experimentation&quot;&gt;Widespread experimentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech giants, supermarket chains, and startups have taken notice of the potential upside of enabling consumers to order food online, and are actively trying to figure out how to pull it off. Amazon Fresh, Google Express, and eBay Now are experimental offerings that are being rolled out in select cities. The likes of Whole Foods and Wal-Mart are cautiously dipping their toes into the online market. And…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2014-10-23/mobile-food-startups-move-beyond-delivery-into-food-prep&quot;&gt;Venture capitalists&lt;/a&gt; are pouring money into online food companies, investing $788 million in the first quarter of 2014 alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these attempts are still in their early days, such widespread experimentation is evidence that today’s business leaders agree that selling food and drink online is a business they can’t afford &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to be part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-08/tech-logos.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A few noteable entrants.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-generation&quot;&gt;A new generation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Millennials&lt;/strong&gt;, those aged 18-34, &lt;strong&gt;spend more money online than any other age group&lt;/strong&gt; — despite having not yet reached their prime spending years. While they earned an average of just $36,000 in 2013, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/the-surprising-demographics-of-who-shops-online-and-on-mobile-2014-6&quot;&gt;5.33% of that was spent online&lt;/a&gt;, totalling just under $2,000 annually. (For comparison, Generation X-ers spent 3.85% of their $48,000 average income.) As millennials increase their earning capacity, they are likely to continue spending a high percentage of their income online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only do millennials spend the most &lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt;, but &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gallup.com/poll/156416/americans-spend-151-week-food-high-income-180.aspx&quot;&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt; found that they also &lt;strong&gt;spend more money on food&lt;/strong&gt; than any other age group, nearly $750 per month. In addition, 70% of them regularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.specialtyfood.com/news/article/todays-consumer-14/&quot;&gt;buy &lt;em&gt;specialty&lt;/em&gt; food items&lt;/a&gt;, a higher percentage than any other generation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In other words, millennials have more of an appetite for buying food products online than any other age group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-12-08/millenial.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Obligatory stock photo of a millennial.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;change-is-in-the-air&quot;&gt;Change is in the air&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A huge untapped market. Widespread experimentation. A new generation coming of age. These are ingredients for disruptive innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Over the next three years, I believe that the famished state of online food commerce will be transformed into a feast of opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch this space.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/08/from-famine-to-feast-foods-online-future.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/12/08/from-famine-to-feast-foods-online-future.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Taking Time Off</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: -1.43em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-11-12/the-cottage.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Our humble autumn abode in the Dordogne region of France.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Thus for the first time since his creation man will be faced with his real, his permanent problem — how to use his freedom from pressing economic cares, how to occupy the leisure, which science and compound interest will have won for him, to live wisely and agreeably and well.” — John Maynard Keynes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I woke up to a cool, crisp November morning. During the night the chill air had managed to gradually, patiently creep in through the windows, under the door. It was cold. Galileo and Atticus, my four- and two-year-old boys, were already into mischief in the living room by the time I emerged from beneath the duvet. The three of us slipped on our waterproof boots, embraced the fresh air, and located the axe in the woodshed. The boys took turns exerting their full strength to cart a hardwood log onto the shopping block, and then scamper a safe distance away so that I could let the axe fall through the air and perform its duty. Half an hour later, the Godin wood burner sung its song of warmth in the kitchen, a day’s supply of fuel stacked snuggly by its side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-11-12/wood-pile.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Wood delivery day.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such simple but satisfying avocations are all too uncommon in the hubbub of modern life — they have been in mine, at least. That is, except for the past few months. After five years of working in a startup — one year of which involved straddling two companies, and a further year multitasking to write a book — I decided to take a break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And so, my family and I have spent August, September, and October camping in Scotland and Cornwall,  cycling through the Cotswolds, and living in the Dordogne region of France, chopping firewood and fuelling the wood burner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-life-of-leisure&quot;&gt;A Life of Leisure?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Maynard Keynes, in his 1930 essay &lt;em&gt;Economic Possibilities for our Grandchildren&lt;/em&gt;, predicted that you and I would only need to work perhaps 15 hours per week, and that the challenge of our generation would be in occupying our overabundant leisure time. How distant from reality this now sounds as, for most of us, work occupies the lion’s share of our attention, effort, and time. Which isn’t a bad thing, for work is about much more than simply making a living; at its best work is challenging, rewarding, and thoroughly enjoyable in its own right. But every so often, it’s worth taking a break from the fast and furious to appreciate life’s simple pleasures, to go outside and chop firewood in the crisp morning air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now three months in, I feel relaxed, rejuvenated, and full of enthusiasm for my next work project, now quietly underway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conclusion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Work hard. Enjoy your work. But take a break every now and then to, in the words of Keynes, “cultivate the art of life itself.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/11/12/on-taking-time-off.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/11/12/on-taking-time-off.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Four Faces of Search</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Search means different things to different people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Twigkit, companies across the gamut of industries use our software to build different types of search-based applications — from behind-the-firewall enterprise search, to public-facing website search, to a variety of bespoke business applications. While powered by the same technology, the business goals and user expectations for search application vary widely from industry to industry. That’s why we recently began exploring the following question with the search team at Google Enterprise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does search mean for the organisations in four particular industries — financial services, manufacturing, media, and the public sector?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from our experience of having worked with numerous customers across each of these industries, we set out to use Twigkit and the Google Search Appliance to build a set of exemplar applications that demonstrate the business value of search for each of these four sectors. Here’s what we came up with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/07/25/four-faces-of-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/07/25/four-faces-of-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2014 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I gave this talk at the UX Scotland conference in Edinburgh on June 19, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browsing the web. Surfing the net. Navigating a website. Such metaphorical language highlights a universal truth of human psychology: we perceive the world, both physical and digital, in spatial terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of today’s web experiences, however, treat information as a book — the table of contents became the navigation menu, the index became the search index, and pages simply became web pages. This vestige of the past is holding us back. To create information environments that are truly coherent, we must view them not as books full of pages, but as spaces to navigate and explore—much like finding one’s way through a city or a museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I call information wayfinding. By synthesising ideas both from information interaction — including berrypicking, information foraging, sensemaking — and from wayfinding, the process of spatial problem solving, we can gain new insights into designing effective digital experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we’ll consider the elements of the information environment: districts, layers, and nodes. We’ll investigate common wayfinding strategies: locate, explore, and meander. And we’ll outline a set of design principles for optimising wayfinding — such as using structured districts, flexible layers, positional cues, survey knowledge, and clear paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come join us in thinking about the future of interacting with information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2014/06/19/information-wayfinding.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2014/06/19/information-wayfinding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience: Full Day Workshop</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop took place at UX Scotland in Edinburgh on June 18, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search is not just a box and 10 blue links. Search is a journey: an exploration where what we encounter along the way changes what we seek. But in order to guide people along this journey, we must understand both the art and science of search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop weaves together the theories of information seeking with the practice of user interface design, providing a comprehensive guide to designing search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will enable you to create better search experiences by equipping you with both a well-rounded understanding of the theories of information seeking, and a sweeping survey of search user interface best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2014/06/18/designing-the-search-experience-ux-scotland-workshop.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2014/06/18/designing-the-search-experience-ux-scotland-workshop.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Better Wayfinding on Pinterest and Spotify</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I want to find some new music to listen to.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I need some inspiration for my bicycle renovation project.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I’m in the mood to watch a thoughtful, uplifting film.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We face these kinds of open-ended tasks everyday, but they are often difficult and frustrating to tackle. (Ever given up in despair after spending half an hour trying to find a film to watch, for instance?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Keyword search is a great tool for answering specific questions, but it’s less useful if we’re not sure exactly what to ask in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinterest and Spotify have both recently made their services more effective at answering such open-ended questions. Pinterest just released what it bills as &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.pinterest.com/post/83772264616/guided-search-a-new-way-to-find-what-youre-looking&quot;&gt;guided search&lt;/a&gt;, while Spotify’s latest version includes a reinvented &lt;a href=&quot;http://news.spotify.com/us/2014/04/02/spotify-paints-it-black-with-new-look/&quot;&gt;browse function&lt;/a&gt;. What can we learn from these two new features?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-types-of-needs&quot;&gt;Three Types of Needs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, lets put these open-ended questions in context. Most information needs that a user has fall into one of three categories (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingthesearchexperience.com&quot;&gt;Designing the Search Experience&lt;/a&gt; for more background):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Locate.&lt;/strong&gt; I know exactly &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; I’m looking for, I just need help finding &lt;em&gt;where&lt;/em&gt; it’s located. For example: &lt;em&gt;I want to listen to Parachutes by Coldplay&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Explore.&lt;/strong&gt; I have an open-ended goal, and the journey — the information I encounter along the way — is as important as the destination itself. The three opening examples all fall into this category.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meander.&lt;/strong&gt; I’m not looking for anything in particular, I just have some spare time and want to have fun. For example: &lt;em&gt;I have a few minutes to kill… lets see what’s happening on Twitter&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keyword search is ideal for &lt;em&gt;locating&lt;/em&gt; known-items, and social networks such as Facebook are happy to help us fill those spare minutes with &lt;em&gt;meandering&lt;/em&gt;. But &lt;em&gt;exploring&lt;/em&gt; remains underserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like to think of exploratory questions as a process of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twigkit.com/blog/2013/11/07/information-wayfinding.html&quot;&gt;wayfinding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. When navigating across a city, a person might use maps, refer to signs, and “follow their noses.” In the same way,  a person may browse, search, and pick up nuggets of information along the way as they explore a digital environment. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, both Pinterest and Spotify heavily relied on keyword search to help people locate the pins or artists, albums, and songs that they already knew about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Each company’s recent improvement, however, makes it easier to find your way when you aren’t sure exactly what you’re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pinterests-guided-search&quot;&gt;Pinterest’s Guided Search&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pinterest’s new guided search feature helps users find their way by suggesting relevant query refinements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets say Harry is considering undertaking a bicycle restoration project and is looking for some inspiration. He could start by simply typing “bicycle” into the search box. While Harry may well get some interesting ideas from the pins that are returned, he would probably do even better with a more precise search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s where the guided search feature kicks in. Having returned results for “bicycle”, Pinterest then suggests a number of related terms that Harry might want to add to his query, such as “Vintage”, “Road”, and “Accessories”. Lets say Harry selected “Road” — he would then be presented with results relevant to both “bicycle” and “road”. He would also be shown a new list of suggested refinements, such as “vintage”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-05-12/pinterest-guided-search.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 1a: Search for &quot;bicycle&quot; in the Pinterest iOS app.&lt;br /&gt;Figure 1b: See a list of suggested refinements, and choose &quot;road&quot;.&lt;br /&gt;Figure 1c: Select &quot;vintage&quot;.&lt;br /&gt; Figure 1d: Results for &quot;vintage road bicycles&quot;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this way, Pinterest is attempting to optimise the process of wayfinding; they are trying to guide users along a journey to help them find what interests them most. Without the guided search feature, users would need to think of the query refinements themselves. But as we know from the principle of recognition over recall, it is much easier to recognise a relevant term than it is to think of it on your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pinterest is certainly not the first to provide such functionality — showing a list of related searches is a common pattern — but Pinterest have made it a focal point of their experience, and have executed the user interface particularly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;browsing-on-spotify&quot;&gt;Browsing on Spotify&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Pinterest, earlier versions of Spotify relied heavily on the user typing in the name of a song, album, or artist into the search box. While this works well for &lt;em&gt;locating&lt;/em&gt;, it’s ineffective at helping people &lt;em&gt;explore&lt;/em&gt;. Along with Spotify’s recent dark-themed redesign, however, came a new “browse” area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-05-12/spotify-genres.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 2. Browsing by genre and mood in Spotify.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than expect the user to know ahead of time what song they want to listen to, Spotify’s browse area presents a listing of 25 “genres and moods”, as they call it: party, workout, chill, country &amp;amp; folk, jazz &amp;amp; blues, and so on. Selecting one of these genres, “Country &amp;amp; Folk”, for instance, then presents a selection of playlists for that particular genre. Playlists under country and folk, for instance, include entries such as beards &amp;amp; flannel, nu-modern, indie folk, and roots revival — each with dozens of tracks that have been tastefully curated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2014-05-12/spotify-playlists.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Figure 3. A collection of playlists within the &quot;Country &amp;amp; Folk&quot; genre.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;better-wayfinding&quot;&gt;Better Wayfinding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Pinterest’s guided search and Spotify’s new browse feature help people &lt;em&gt;wayfind&lt;/em&gt; — to explore their open-ended questions. They help people hone in on the treasure buried in the midst of a vast sea of pins and songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more ideas on designing for effective wayfinding, I’ve outlined six guidelines in a recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2014/03/information-wayfinding-part-3-designing-for-wayfinding-1.php&quot;&gt;UX Matters article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/05/12/better-wayfinding-on-pinterest-and-spotify.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/05/12/better-wayfinding-on-pinterest-and-spotify.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding, Part 3: Designing for Wayfinding</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;That is the question I want to consider in this third and final installment of my series on information wayfinding. In Part 1, I argued that we must move beyond thinking of information architecture as designing wayfinding for a book of pages and, instead, think in terms of a spatial environment. In Part 2, I compared interacting with information to the process of finding one’s way through a city, then defined three elements of the information environment, shown in Figure 1: districts, layers, and nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll first look at how people move through such information environments—the behavior of wayfinding. Then I’ll outline a set of guidelines for building Web sites and applications that enable people to make sense of continually expanding volumes of information without their becoming overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/03/10/information-wayfinding-part-3.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/03/10/information-wayfinding-part-3.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Look Back at 2013</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;2013 was a good year for Twigkit. We released exciting technology, worked with great customers and partners, participated in the search community, and grew our team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/01/15/a-look-back-at-2013.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2014/01/15/a-look-back-at-2013.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot; style=&quot;margin-top: -1.43em;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/1-information-overload.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Information overload.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are drowning in information. As more and more data floods in, we find ourselves in a state of information anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Big data” is today’s buzzword of choice. People like to talk about using clever technology to “make sense of big data.” I would suggest, however, that &lt;em&gt;big data is not a technology problem. It’s a people problem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe the question that we need to ask is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How can we make ever-growing volumes of information accessible and useful to people without overwhelming them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my talk yesterday at the Enterprise Search Summit in Washington D.C., I attempted to outline a new vocabulary with which we can use to answer that question. But first, it’s worth putting the problem in context by reviewing the history of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-brief-history-of-information&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For our purposes, lets consider two eras of information: the analog era, and the digital era. The analog era begins with the written word, and concludes with the printed book, while the digital era covers early web pages through to our present state of information overload.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-tablet-and-the-written-word&quot;&gt;The Tablet And The Written Word&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/2-cuiniform.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A cuneiform tablet.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A cuneiform tablet.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its earliest form, the written word was meant to be read &lt;em&gt;linearly&lt;/em&gt;. It had no table of contents and no index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-scroll-and-the-table-of-contents&quot;&gt;The Scroll And The Table Of Contents&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/3-scroll.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A scroll.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A scroll.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scarcely a format conducive for rapidly jumping from place to place, scrolls were also intended to be read linearly. Despite this constraint, the first tables of contents were developed for scroll manuscripts. In the first century A.D., for instance, Pliny the Elder preceded his 37-volume &lt;em&gt;Natural History&lt;/em&gt; with a detailed table of contents. Such tables distilled the contents of a work into a taxonomy of volumes, sections, and chapters so that a reader would not have to scroll through the entire work to find their topic of interest. This marks the beginning of &lt;em&gt;non-linear&lt;/em&gt; information retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-printing-press-and-the-index&quot;&gt;The Printing Press And The Index&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/4-index.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A book index.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A book index.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the development of the printing press, however, that the taxonomical organization of the book — the table of contents — was augmented with a secondary organizational scheme: the index. Having transformed leafless, handwritten scrolls into mass-market books with numbered pages, the printing press made it practical to create, replicate, and use an alphabetized index of topics. If the reader could not locate their topic of choice in the table of contents, they could look it up in the much more granular index and jump directly to the relevant page in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-early-internet-and-the-web-page-1990s&quot;&gt;The Early Internet And The Web Page (1990’s)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/5-altavista.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Early internet.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Enter the world wide web.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early World Wide Web simply replicated the format of the book in digital form. The book became the website, the table of contents became the website’s navigation, the index became the search box, and most obviously of all, book pages simply became Web pages. At that time, search performed exactly the same role on a website as the index had performed in a book — it was an alternative way of locating a page of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-cms-and-the-search-engine-2000s&quot;&gt;The CMS And The Search Engine (2000’s)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advent of Content Management System (and the Digital Asset Management System in the enterprise) meant that content was being “tagged” — enriched with structured metadata. At the same time, modern search engines were emerging with the ability to facet on this metadata. Together, these developments made search much more useful than before — helping people explore as well as locate. However, search remained subservient to navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While search was still playing the role of a book index, faceted navigation meant that instead of there being a just single index of keywords, each facet became an index in its own right, thus compounding the usefulness of search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, tension increased between the table of contents and the index, between the interaction methods of navigation and search. People had to use separate interfaces for each of these two functions. And behind the scenes, they were each powered by different technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/6-nyt.png&quot; alt=&quot;The New York Times.&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Left: the table of contents. Right: the index. Why such different interaction models?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;big-data-and-information-wayfinding-2010s&quot;&gt;Big Data And Information Wayfinding (2010’s)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While CMS and DAM systems are still used to manage content and documents, the modern company now has myriad additional sources of information with which to reckon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The segregated architecture of navigation from search is creaking under the weight of ever increasing volumes of information. While separating the table of contents from the index is fine for a book, the metaphor has been stretched to its limits and needs replacing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-information-environment-a-not-so-new-metaphor&quot;&gt;The Information Environment: A not-so-new metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there is an obvious alternative. Consider the language we use to describe our interaction with computers: browsing the web, surfing the net, navigating a website, traversing a hierarchy, going back, scrolling up and down, returning home. Our history of using computers to interact with information is littered with such metaphors. Haphazard though they may be, they highlight a universal reality of human psychology: we perceive the world — both physical and digital — in &lt;em&gt;spatial&lt;/em&gt; terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mankind evolved in a world of space and time. Our memories evolved to record events that transpire in space and time. Modern attempts to externalize and enlarge that memory should not, and probably need not, neglect its spatiotemporal dimensions.” — George A. Miller, 1968&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to jettison the old “information as a book” metaphor, and embrace the even older “information as a physical environment” metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;elements-of-the-city-image&quot;&gt;Elements Of The City Image&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before unpacking the implications of the “information as a physical environment” metaphor, its worth quickly considering physical environments in their own right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his 1960 book, &lt;em&gt;The Image of the City&lt;/em&gt;, Kevin Lynch famously outlined five elements of the city image. Crucially, he considered not just the physical qualities of the environment, but sought to understand the city from a human the perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We must consider not just the city as a thing itself, but the city being perceived by its inhabitants.” — Kevin Lynch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/8-elements.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elements of the city image&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five elements Lynch identified are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paths&lt;/strong&gt;. The roads, footpaths, and transportation lines by which a person moves through the city.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edges&lt;/strong&gt;. The walls, railway lines, and shores which form the boundaries between areas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Districts&lt;/strong&gt;. Broad areas of the city that possess their own sense of identity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nodes&lt;/strong&gt;. Points of interest which a person may enter, such as a junction, building, or city square.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Landmarks&lt;/strong&gt;. A physical structure — such as a sign, building facade, or mountain — which serves as an external reference point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynch’s ideas on how people view and move through a city are insightful precursors to how people conceptualize and navigate information spaces today. But enough about physical elements. What about information environments?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;elements-of-the-information-environment&quot;&gt;Elements of the Information Environment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we must define information environments in their own right:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;An information environment is a place someone goes to seek information in order to satisfy an information need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Websites, mobile applications, scientific databases, corporate intranets, and other collections of information all qualify as information environments. Lets select a few example information environments to frame the discussion that follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon.com&lt;/strong&gt;. People visit this store to look for and buy products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New York Times&lt;/strong&gt;. People come to this environment in search of news.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Company intranet&lt;/strong&gt;. People come to this area to find documents and information relevant to their job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following Lynch’s example, we must look beyond the brick and mortar of the environment itself to understand how people, the waypfinders who visit the territory, interact with and conceptualize that environment. To that end, I think that most information environments consist of three principle elements: districts, layers, and nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;large&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/districts-layers-nodes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Elements of the information environment.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;districts&quot;&gt;Districts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Districts are the main categories into which an environment can be logically divided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/districts.png&quot; alt=&quot;Districts.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any environment of substantial size, whether a city or a website, will inevitably be subdivided into smaller areas. London, for example, has districts such as Mayfair, Soho, and Southbank, while The New York Times (both in its print newspaper and on its website) has districts including World News, Politics, and Technology. Small environments may contain just a few flat districts, but bustling environments often feature rich taxonomies of districts within districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layers&quot;&gt;Layers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Layers are secondary categories which describe a specific facet of a given node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/layers.png&quot; alt=&quot;Layers.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Districts form the primary structure of the environment, but there are countless additional criteria that affect what a person may be looking for. Someone trying to find a place to eat in London’s Soho district, for instance, probably doesn’t want just any restaurant in the area; instead, she might be looking for a restaurant in a certain price range that serves a certain type of cuisine. In addition to a geographic preference, in other words, she also has a price criterion and a cuisine criterion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These secondary criteria can be treated as &lt;em&gt;layers&lt;/em&gt;. While city districts bound an area along two dimensions — length and width — layers introduce a third dimension: depth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some digital maps allow users to select the layers of information to be presented — such as topography, roads, landmarks, and restaurants. Similarly, the layers of an information environment enable users to mould their view of the environment so that it aligns with their criteria. Layers help them filter out the noise and tune in the signal that resonates with their own mental model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nodes&quot;&gt;Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;small&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/nodes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Nodes.&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within a district there are many nodes — precise points in the environment that we might otherwise refer to as a Web page, document, or record. There are two different types of nodes: informational and directional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Informational nodes, as the name suggests, contain information about a specific concept. Viewing the details of a product on Amazon.com, reading a New York Times news article, and scanning the HR vacation policy page on your company’s intranet are all examples of interacting with informational nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directional nodes, on the other hand, do not provide content of their own, but help direct people to the relevant informational nodes that do. Somewhat analogous to a cluster of directional signs at a large intersection, or a directory of shops at a mall or airport, directional nodes often list the key informational nodes within a given district or layer. Examples of directional nodes include viewing the HR section on a company’s intranet, clicking on World News category at NYTimes.com, and browsing used English-language hardcover economics books on Amazon.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-wayfinding-the-human-element&quot;&gt;Information Wayfinding: The Human Element&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do people interact with the elements of an information environment? I think of the process as &lt;em&gt;information wayfinding&lt;/em&gt;. I’ve thrown the term around once or twice already, but we haven’t yet defined it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wayfinding&lt;/em&gt; itself is the collection of cognitive processes people use to navigate physical environments. At its root it is spatial problem solving, a process closely studied by environmental physiologists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Information way finding, then, is the collection of cognitive processes people use to navigate information environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People often engage in three different types of wayfinding, what I label as: locate, explore, and meander.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;locate&quot;&gt;Locate&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Who was the director of the film ‘The Third Man’?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What is the population of London?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“When are expense filings due?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Where is Jimmy’s Pizza”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are all examples of “locate” information needs. In each case, the user has articulated precisely what they’re looking for. They just need help locating it. We sometimes call these “lookup” queries, and there is typically one right answer to the question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;explore&quot;&gt;Explore&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What kind of car should I buy?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Where should I go on holiday?”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“What film should I watch this evening?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exploring is much more open-ended than locating. When people explore, the journey is as important as the destination. As people encounter new information, their information need evolves, resulting in an iterative, ongoing process. In other words, users engage in information wayfinding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcia Bates has described this process as “berrypicking” — people move from one source to another picking up nuggets of information along the way. Peter Pirolli and Stuart Card describe the process as “information foraging,” where people follow “information scent” as they go. Both of these models depict information seeking in spatial terms, and reinforce the concept of information wayfinding as a result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/berrypicking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Marcia Bates&#39; berrypicking model of information seeking&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Marcia Bates&#39; berrypicking model of information seeking.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;meander&quot;&gt;Meander&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While locating and exploring are both prompted by an information need, there is a third category which is not: meandering. People sometimes aren’t looking for anything in particular, but might be prompted by other motives such as having fun or killing time. Checking email or social networks while waiting for the bus to arrive is just one example of meandering behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;principles-for-a-new-architecture&quot;&gt;Principles for a New Architecture&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far I’ve proposed that a collection of information is best thought about in terms of an information environment, that the information environment consists of three distinct elements, and that wayfinding is a useful way for considering how people interact with these environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I would like to propose six principles that should guide how we go about constructing information environments: structured districts, flexible layers, positional cues, survey knowledge, clear paths, and coherent interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To more effectively demonstrate these principles, one day last week I built an application using Twigkit and a collection of excellent film data curated by Nasser Ahmed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;structured-districts&quot;&gt;Structured Districts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve said that districts are the main categories into which an environment can be divided. Logical, clear districts are important to help users understand the information environment at its most basic level. Districts should correspond with the user’s own mental model. When people think about films, for instance, they think in terms in genres: a film is an action film or a drama film, a comedy or a thriller. Virtually every domain has some dominate organisation scheme that should form the districts of the information environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Districts should be clearly presented to users, perhaps in a form resembling traditional web navigation. Correspondingly, the URL scheme should also be based on districts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/structured-districts.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Structured districts&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;flexible-layers&quot;&gt;Flexible Layers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to districts — which serve as the primary organisation scheme — users should also be able to filter by secondary criteria, which we’ve said resemble layers of the information environment. The flexibility of layers is a vital companion to the rigid hierarchy of districts, and the two should operate in tandem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/flexible-layers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Flexible layers&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;positional-cues&quot;&gt;Positional Cues&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like a “you are here” marker on a map, positional cues help users orientate themselves within the information environment. Most frequently, positional cues take the form of breadcrumbs — they indicate the district in which the user is browsing, what layers they have applied, and any search terms they have entered. These positional cues give users a sense of security, and avert any feelings of lostness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/positional-cues.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Positional cues&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;survey-knowledge&quot;&gt;Survey Knowledge&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helping users gain survey knowledge is a second form of enhancing orientation. But while positional cues more often depict where the user has been, survey knowledge helps them ascertain where they should go next. Like studying a map or looking at the landscape from the top of a mountain, survey knowledge gives users an overview of the information environment. Data visualisation — from subtle indicators to full fledged charts and graphs — are an excellent tool for enhancing survey knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/survey-knowledge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Survey knowledge&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;clear-paths&quot;&gt;Clear Paths&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a physical environment, having a clear line of sight to the destination greatly simplifies the act of getting there. It would be orders of magnitude more difficult, I’m sure you’d agree, to navigate to a destination blindfolded. So in information environments, having clear paths ensures that users always have a path onward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good example of this principle is having links to related content. When viewing an information node (what we often call a “detail page”) for a film, for instance, having clear paths to similar films, to films by the same director, starring the same actors, and so forth, gives users a sufficient number of paths forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;medium&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/resources/images/2013-11-07/clear-paths.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Clear paths&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coherent-interaction&quot;&gt;Coherent Interaction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most importantly of all, I believe that interacting with districts, layers, and keyword search should be a single, seamless experience. Layers should not only be available in “search mode,” and keyword search should not be divorced from districts. Instead, users should be able to navigate to districts, apply layers, and perform searches iteratively and conjunctively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s return to the question we asked at the beginning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How can we make ever-growing volumes of information accessible and useful to people without overwhelming them?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe we must:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider information as a spatial environment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understand how users find their way through information environments, and support them along that journey.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unify navigation and search into a single, coherent experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If we pursue these three things, then search will no longer be just a box in the top right corner, but will become the de facto way people interact with large information environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the world’s most successful online properties — Google, Facebook, Amazon, eBay — have already embraced these three tenets. The question is: will you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;slides&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the full slidedeck from my talk at the Enterprise Search Summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/kHOd1PLi5A53i2&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tylertate/information-wayfinding-the-future-of-search&quot; title=&quot;Information Wayfinding: The Future of Search&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Information Wayfinding: The Future of Search&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/tylertate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tyler Tate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/11/07/information-wayfinding.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/11/07/information-wayfinding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding: The Future of Search</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;People’s interactions with information environments are strikingly similar to how we navigate physical environments. I believe that embracing this spatial approach to information — what I call information wayfinding — can help us build environments conducive to the people who use them. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at the Enterprise Search Summit in Washington D.C. on November 6, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/11/06/information-wayfinding-the-future-of-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/11/06/information-wayfinding-the-future-of-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience: Half-day Workshop</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Search is not just a box and ten blue links. Search is a journey: an exploration where what we encounter along the way changes what we seek. But in order to guide people along this journey, we must understand both the art and science of search. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop weaves together the theories of information seeking with the practice of user interface design, providing a comprehensive guide to designing search. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 1 
Participants will first learn about the concepts behind search, including: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The psychology of users — such as their level of expertise, cognitive style, and learning style &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Models of information seeking and information needs — including how they’ve been shaped by theories such as information foraging and sensemaking &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The role of context — from task, to physical, social context &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this conceptual investigation, participants will have a guided, hands-on opportunity to identify the spectrum of information needs their search applications should address. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 2 
Moving from theory to practice, we will then apply the concepts from Part 1 to the actual design of effective experiences. We will start by reviewing user interface patterns for: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entering the query — including the search box, as-you-type suggestions, advanced search, and non-textual input &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Search result layout — from lists and grids, to maps, augmented reality, and voice 
Result manipulation controls — such as pagination and sorting &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ins-and-outs of faceted navigation &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile and responsive design considerations &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After considering these design patterns, participants will then have a chance to sketch their search user interfaces ideas for both desktop and mobile environments. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, this workshop will enable you to create better search experiences by equipping you with both a well-rounded understanding of the theories of information seeking, and a sweeping survey of search user interface best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/09/04/workshop-designing-the-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/09/04/workshop-designing-the-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Retina Images Using Media Queries and LESS CSS: A responsive approach to supporting multiple pixel densities</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve owned a retina-equipped MacBook Pro since January, and for me, there’s no going back. With retina versions of the iPhone, iPad, and many &lt;a href=&quot;http://developer.android.com/guide/webapps/targeting.html&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/a&gt; devices, supporting high-density devices has become unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twigkit.com/&quot;&gt;Twigkit&lt;/a&gt;, our library of user interface components has long been image-free. We were early adopters of font icons, whose vector format scales to any screen resolution or pixel density. When I set out to redesign our marketing site a couple of months ago, however, I needed an approach for images that would minimise bandwidth for low-density devices, while maximising quality for high-density screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;javascript-vs-css&quot;&gt;JavaScript vs. CSS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two main approaches to delivering images for multiple pixel densities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use image tags with JavaScript&lt;/strong&gt; to replace the image’s source attribute when appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use CSS background images with media queries&lt;/strong&gt; to override the background image when appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both approaches are technically sound. But all else being equal, I personally prefer to use CSS for presentation and reserve JavaScript for interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;background-images&quot;&gt;Background images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CSS approach relies on all images being set through the &lt;code&gt;background-image&lt;/code&gt; property. If we have two images to display that are both 450x300, for instance, we could do as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;figure id=&quot;desert&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;figure id=&quot;camel&quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the CSS:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure {
	width: 450px;
	height: 300px;
}
figure#desert {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);
}
figure#camel {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-media-query&quot;&gt;The Media Query&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the images displayed as &lt;code&gt;background-images&lt;/code&gt;, we can then use a media query to detect the pixel density of the device viewing our page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
	figure#desert {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune_2x.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
	figure#camel {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/camel_2x.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;code&gt;min-resolution: 192dpi&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3.org/TR/css3-mediaqueries/#resolution&quot;&gt;W3C-approved&lt;/a&gt; mechanism for targeting pixel density, it’s not yet &lt;a href=&quot;http://drewwells.net/blog/2013/working-with-dppx/&quot;&gt;well supported&lt;/a&gt;. For now, the vendor specific &lt;code&gt;-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;min--moz-device-pixel-ratio&lt;/code&gt; (yes, believe it or not that Mozilla prefix is &lt;a href=&quot;http://menacingcloud.com/?c=highPixelDensityDisplays&quot;&gt;correct&lt;/a&gt;) are well supported by browsers likely to be used on high-density devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will notice that this media query adds a &lt;code&gt;_2x&lt;/code&gt; suffix to the filenames of our two images. This assumes that we have created these image files, and that they are twice the resolution of the original. In other words, if the original image is 450x300 pixels, our &lt;code&gt;_2x&lt;/code&gt; images should be 900x600.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, the web browser on a retina device will automatically scale an image to its actual pixel size. That is, our 900x450 image would be scaled to occupy a full 900x450 “virtual pixels” on the screen, whereas what we actually want is for the image to be scaled down to the original 450x300 area. To achieve this, we can set &lt;code&gt;background-size: 100%;&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://quirksmode.org/css/backgrounds-borders/&quot;&gt;This&lt;/a&gt; instructs the browser to make the background image equal in width to its container.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nested-media-queries-with-less&quot;&gt;Nested Media Queries with LESS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I’m sure you’ll agree, we’ve hardly broken new ground. The biggest problem I have with the above approach, however, is that it requires the designer to organise their CSS according to pixel densities. Instead of structuring stylesheets around the logical structure of the website, in other words, it forces us to have different stylesheets (or different blocks within a single stylesheet) to address each pixel density that we want to target. I don’t like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, CSS preprocessors like &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesscss.org/#-nested-media-queries&quot;&gt;LESS&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#media&quot;&gt;SASS&lt;/a&gt; support nesting media queries within selectors. For example, using LESS we could restructure our stylesheet as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure {
	width: 450px;
	height: 300px;
}
figure#desert {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);

	@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune_2x.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
figure#camel {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);

	@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/camel_2x.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the compiled output of this stylesheet would resemble the original example, LESS’s nested media query support allows us to structure our stylesheet more naturally. However, having to remember to add these extra few lines for every image is still tedious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mixin-take-1&quot;&gt;The Mixin, Take 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS preprocessors provide a second tool which can make this process easier: &lt;em&gt;mixins&lt;/em&gt;. The SASS documentation describes a &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com/docs/yardoc/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#mixins&quot;&gt;mixin&lt;/a&gt; as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mixins allow you to define styles that can be re-used throughout the stylesheet… They can also take arguments which allows you to produce a wide variety of styles with very few mixins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s experiment by moving our media query to a mixin called &lt;code&gt;.background-image()&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.background-image(@image) {
	background-image: url(@image);

	@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
		background-image: url(@image);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will notice that the mixin accepts an &lt;code&gt;@image&lt;/code&gt; parameter, which is then used to set the &lt;code&gt;background-image&lt;/code&gt;. Having defined this mixin, we could then rewrite our primary stylesheet to reference it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure {
	width: 450px;
	height: 300px;
}
figure#desert {
	.background-image(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);
}
figure#camel {
	.background-image(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our compiled CSS would then look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure {
	width: 450px;
	height: 300px;
}
figure#desert {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);
}
@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
	figure#desert {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
figure#camel {
	background-image: url(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);
}
@media only screen and (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
	figure#camel {
		background-image: url(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to see how a mixin could simplify configuration. Of course, this mixin isn’t yet doing it’s job; you’ll notice that the retina image is still pointing to &lt;code&gt;images/sand-dune.jpg&lt;/code&gt;, and not the &lt;code&gt;images/sand-dune_2x.jpg&lt;/code&gt; that we need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-regular-expression&quot;&gt;The Regular Expression&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step requires a bit of a leap. In order to add the &lt;code&gt;_2x&lt;/code&gt; suffix to the image path, we could have our &lt;code&gt;.background-image()&lt;/code&gt; mixin use a regular expression to split the image path into two parts — filename and extension. We can then piece the path back together, inserting the &lt;code&gt;_2x&lt;/code&gt; suffix between them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, stay with me here. Lets first prototype our regular expression in JavaScript. I’ve created a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net/g7rqt/&quot;&gt;fiddle&lt;/a&gt; where you can run this code for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;var image = &#39;../images/image.png&#39;;
var regex = /(.*)\.(jpg|jpeg|png|gif)/;
var match = regex.exec(image);
if (match != null) {
    alert(&quot;background-image: url(&#39;&quot;+match[1]+&quot;_2x.&quot;+match[2]+&quot;&#39;);&quot;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The regular expression has two &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.regular-expressions.info/brackets.html&quot;&gt;capture groups&lt;/a&gt;, which are denoted by parenthesis: &lt;code&gt;(.*)&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;(jpg|jpeg|png|gif)&lt;/code&gt;. The second capture group matches any of the listed extensions: &lt;code&gt;jpg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;jpeg&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;png&lt;/code&gt;, or &lt;code&gt;gif&lt;/code&gt;. The first capture group captures everything before the full stop. Then, in the &lt;code&gt;alert()&lt;/code&gt;, we reconstruct the image path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-mixin-take-2&quot;&gt;The Mixin, Take 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve created a regular expression that works, we can incorporate this into our mixin by taking advantage of LESS’s ability to evaluate JavaScript expressions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.background-image(@image){
	@filename:  ~`/(.*)\.(jpg|jpeg|png|gif)/.exec(@{image})[1]`;
	@extension: ~`/(.*)\.(jpg|jpeg|png|gif)/.exec(@{image})[2]`;
	background-image: ~`&quot;url(@{filename}.@{extension})&quot;`;

	@media (-webkit-min-device-pixel-ratio: 2) {
		background-image: ~`&quot;url(@{filename}_2x.@{extension})&quot;`;
		background-size: 100%;
	}
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there is no concept of arrays in LESS, I’ve had to run the same regular expression twice, once to grab the filename, and again to get the extension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the mixin now equipped with our regular expression, we can very simply reference our images and be certain that the correct resolution image is being delivered to the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;figure {
	width: 450px;
	height: 300px;
}
figure#desert {
	.background-image(&#39;images/sand-dune.jpg&#39;);
}
figure#camel {
	.background-image(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can view a &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.github.io/background-image/demo.html&quot;&gt;working demo&lt;/a&gt; of this solution, as well as &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/tylertate/background-image&quot;&gt;browse the code&lt;/a&gt; on GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limitations&quot;&gt;Limitations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has one particular limitation that it’s important to point out. When compiled, each reference to the &lt;code&gt;.background-image()&lt;/code&gt; mixin results in a few lines of CSS (in this case, five lines). A quick test seems to indicate that about five invocations of the mixin result in about 1 kilobyte of uncompressed CSS. This is acceptable if there are a couple dozen images involved, but not if there are hundreds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advantages&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, this approach of using background images, media queries, and a LESS mixin in combination does have a number of significant advantages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It relies purely on CSS — no JavaScript is required&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s not necessary to restructure your stylesheets to support multiple pixel densities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The mixin abstracts the media queries and references to retina images, so it’s not necessary to add any extra configuration to main stylesheets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The method for referencing images — &lt;code&gt;.background-image(&#39;images/camel.jpg&#39;)&lt;/code&gt; is in keeping with CSS syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/06/11/retina-images-using-media-queries-and-LESS-CSS.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/06/11/retina-images-using-media-queries-and-LESS-CSS.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/05/15/designing-the-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/05/15/designing-the-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding, Part 2: Elements of the Information Environment</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In Part 1 of this series, I argued that vestiges of the pre-Web, print era still haunt digital experiences. To create information environments that are truly coherent, we must view them not as books full of pages, but as spaces to navigate and explore—much like finding our way through a city or a museum. This is what I call information wayfinding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, I’ll scrutinize the nature of information environments by investigating their most fundamental elements. In doing so, my ambition is nothing less than to subtly reframe the way we think about interacting with information on Web sites, in mobile applications, and in other digital experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/05/06/information-wayfinding-part-2.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/05/06/information-wayfinding-part-2.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Search is not just a box and ten blue links. Search is a journey: an exploration where what we encounter along the way changes what we seek. But in order to guide people along this journey, we must understand both the art and science of search.In this talk Tyler Tate, cofounder of TwigKit and coauthor of the new book Designing the Search Experience, weaves together the theories of information seeking with the practice of user interface design, providing a comprehensive guide to designing search.Pulling from a wealth of research conducted over the last 30 years, Tyler begins by establishing a framework of search and discovery. He outlines cognitive attributes of users—including their level of expertise, cognitive style, and learning style; describes models of information seeking and how they’ve been shaped by theories such as information foraging and sensemaking; and reviews the role that task, physical, social, and environmental context plays in the search process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tyler then moves from theory to practice, drawing on his experience of designing 50+ search user interfaces to provide practical guidance for common search requirements. He describes best practices and demonstrates reams of examples for everything from entering the query (including the search box, as-you-type suggestions, advanced search, and non-textual input), to the layout of search results (such as lists, grids, maps, augmented reality, and voice), to result manipulation (e.g. pagination and sorting) and, last but not least, the ins-and-outs of faceted navigation. Through it all, Tyler also addresses mobile interface design and how responsive design techniques can be used to achieve cross-platform search.This intensive talk will enable you to create better search experiences by equipping you with a well-rounded understanding of the theories of information seeking, and providing you with a sweeping survey of search user interface best practices.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/05/03/designing-the-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/05/03/designing-the-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding, Part 1: A Not-So-New Metaphor</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Browsing the Web. Surfing the Net. Navigating a Web site. Traversing a hierarchy. Going back. Scrolling up and down. Returning home. We’ve seen such metaphors throughout our history of using computers to interact with information. Haphazard though they may seem be, these metaphors highlight a universal reality of human psychology: we perceive the world—both physical and digital—in spatial terms.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/04/01/information-wayfinding-part-1.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/04/01/information-wayfinding-part-1.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Mobile Search: A workshop for eBay Classifieds Group</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/03/07/designing-mobile-search-ebay-classifieds-group-workshop.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/03/07/designing-mobile-search-ebay-classifieds-group-workshop.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Wayfinding</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Presented at the European Bioinformatics Institute in Cambridge, UK on February 26. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to @francisrowland for inviting me, and for the excellent blog coverage: http://ebiinterfaces.wordpress.com/2013/02/27/information-wayfinding-tyler-tate/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/26/information-wayfinding.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/26/information-wayfinding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Cross-Channel Experiences</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Tyler Tate will present a discussion of how we can use information needs to guide design that works across a range of channels. He will also cover practical things we can do to help us meet these design challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As people interact with information across a growing number of channels—from computers and phones to paper and the built environment—the emerging practice of cross-channel design is becoming ever more important. In fact, the most successful businesses of both today and tomorrow will be those who can provide cohesive experiences to their customers across the numerous channels that those customers demand. However, architecting effective cross-channel experiences requires a fresh approach, new skills, and novel design methods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk Tyler Tate, author of Designing the Search Experience and cofounder of Twigkit, sets out to provide all three. He begins by establishing a theoretical foundation for cross-channel information interaction, pulling from the fields of information retrieval and human-information interaction. Central to that framework is a matrix of information needs that synthesizes research from Gary Marchionini and Andrei Broder with recent studies of mobile behavior by Karen Church, Timothy Sohn, and others, providing a realistic understanding of the many ways in which people interact with information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving from theory to practice, Tyler next delves into four principles for designing cohesive cross-channel experiences, each complete with examples: 
1. Division of labor. Each channel within the ecosystem should focus on what it does best.
2. Consistency. Consistency across the ecosystem should be balanced across two dimensions: realm and nature.
3. Continuity. Propagate the user’s state across all channels of the ecosystem.
4. Persistence. Enable users to access from any channel the information they’ve stored, organized, and enriched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tyler then ends by outlining two hands-on methods that can be used today to build effective cross-channel experiences:
 1. The cross-channel blueprint. The blueprint provides an overview of the ecosystem’s two most fundamental attributes: the channels of which it’s composed, and the user actions it must facilitate.
2. The experience map. A service design tool, the experience map captures how users traverse the ecosystem’s many parts. 
As we journey deeper into the post-desktop era, the cross-channel experiences that emerge will either make or break our businesses. This talk will help prepare you to lead your organization successfully into the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–
For more on this topic, see:
* http://www.slideshare.net/tylertate/designing-crosschannel-experiences
* http://uxmag.com/articles/investigating-cross-channel-consistency
* http://uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2011/10/the-rise-of-cross-channel-ux-design.php
* http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-836/paper3.pdf
* http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/02/21/cross-channel-ia-blueprint.html
* http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/19/the-experience-map.html&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/25/cross-channel-information-interaction.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/25/cross-channel-information-interaction.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Interaction as Spatial Problem Solving</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A continuation of last week’s blog post, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/13/out-with-the-old-in-with-the-older.html&quot;&gt;Out with the Old, In with the Older&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-brief-history-of-wayfinding&quot;&gt;A brief history of wayfinding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kevin Lynch coined the term “wayfinding” in his 1960 book, &lt;em&gt;The Image of the City&lt;/em&gt;. Lynch recognized that one’s ability to navigate a city is closely related to how spatially oriented the person is within that city. He quantified this as a city’s “imagability”; that is, its likelihood of evoking a strong image in the observer, and therefore enhancing orientation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architect and environmental psychologist Romedi Passini further developed the concept of wayfinding in the 1970s and 80s, defining the term simply as “spatial problem solving.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-seeking-as-wayfinding&quot;&gt;Information seeking as wayfinding&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wayfinding has much in common with how we know people to interact with information. In particular, Marcia Bates’s berrypicking model of information seeking portrays a process where, to paraphrase Peter Morville, what you find along the way changes what you seek. Likewise, Peter Pirolli and Stuart Card’s information foraging theory compares information seeking to rummaging for food in the forest, where users follow information scent as they sniff their way onwards. In both cases, information seeking is presented in terms of spatial problem solving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;on-metaphor&quot;&gt;On metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The metaphor we use to understand the web is a big deal. George Lakoff and Mark Johnson convey the importance of conceptual metaphors in their book &lt;em&gt;Metaphors We Live By&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Our concepts structure what we perceive, how we get around in the world, and how we relate to other people. Our conceptual system thus plays a central role in defining our everyday realities. If we are right in suggesting that our conceptual system is largely metaphorical, then the way we think, what we experience, and what we do every day is very much a matter of metaphor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;all-change-please&quot;&gt;All change please&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we are to build modern information environments that are coherent — which are “imageable” and facilitate orientation — then we should embrace information wayfinding as a new spatial metaphor for the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/20/information-interaction-as-wayfinding.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/20/information-interaction-as-wayfinding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Out with the Old, In with the Older</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Browsing the web. Surfing the net. Navigating a website. Traversing a hierarchy. Going back. Scrolling up and down. Returning home. Our history of using computers to interact with information is littered with such metaphors. Haphazard though they may be, they highlight a universal truth of human psychology: we perceive the world — both physical and digital —  in spatial terms. As George A. Miller remarked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Mankind evolved in a world of space and time. Our memories evolved to record events that transpire in space and time. Modern attempts to externalise and enlarge that memory should not, and probably need not, neglect its spatiotemporal dimensions.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This insight is as important today as when it was written in 1968. However, despite mankind’s age-old proclivity towards spatial organization, the majority of today’s web experiences are built to resemble a relatively more recent invention: the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-book&quot;&gt;The book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Books are characterised by:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pages of information organized into sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A table of contents that lists those sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An index of all the concepts mentioned throughout the book &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-website&quot;&gt;The website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The architecture of most websites still follows this same pattern:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pages of information organised into sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A navigation bar that lists those sections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A search box for finding any concept mentioned on the website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-outdated-metaphor&quot;&gt;An outdated metaphor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is understandable. As content shifted from print to digital in the early days of the web, the methods from the old medium were transferred to the new. While this may have been expedient, the practicality of the book metaphor has faded, and is now holding us back. Consider these two questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do most websites force users to choose between navigating and searching, rather than allowing them to do both in unison?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do most websites not allow users to filter content by criteria such as date, format, price, or rating while browsing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not because users don’t want it (more on this in a future post), or that the technology doesn’t exist. It’s simply because the architects of such websites are still applying book-like-thinking to a very un-book-like medium. They are tiptoeing around a local optimum rather than scouting out the mountain in the distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We need a metaphor for interacting with information that acknowledges the spatial reality of human psychology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-to-the-future&quot;&gt;Looking to the future&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The time has come to adopt a more appropriate metaphor for interacting with digital information, one that acknowledges the spatial reality of human psychology. It’s time to embrace  &lt;strong&gt;information wayfinding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to investigating the concept of information wayfinding over a series of upcoming posts, so stay tuned! In the meantime, I’d love to hear your thoughts about the ideas discussed so far.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/13/out-with-the-old-in-with-the-older.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/13/out-with-the-old-in-with-the-older.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Information Seeking</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/12/information-seeking.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2013/02/12/information-seeking.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From the Page to the City: Quotations from Kevin Lynch&#39;s &#39;The Image of the City&#39;</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2013-02-05/lynch-legend.jpg&quot; width=&quot;722&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;A legend from Kevin Lynch&#39;s book &#39;The Image of the City&#39;.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s time to think differently about how people interact with information. The dominant metaphor of the last five hundred years — the &lt;em&gt;page&lt;/em&gt; — is coming to a close, and a new metaphor is in order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, books were the universal repositories of information from the time of Gutenberg until the birth of the world wide web. Since then, web pages have been organized into websites with navigation and keyword search in the same way that printed pages were organized into books with a table of contents and an index. In other words, the page metaphor remains intact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I hope to elaborate on why the page metaphor is holding us back, and explore the metaphor that is poised to replace it: namely, information interaction as &lt;strong&gt;spatial problem solving&lt;/strong&gt;, popularly known as &lt;strong&gt;wayfinding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0262620014/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0262620014&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=dtse-21&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2013-02-05/the-image-of-the-city.jpg&quot; width=&quot;380&quot; class=&quot;onethirds-width&quot; style=&quot;float: right; margin: 0 -5% 1em 1em;&quot; alt=&quot;The Image of the City&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-image-of-the-city&quot;&gt;The Image of the City&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I simply want to share a few excerpts from a book I’ve been reading: Kevin Lynch’s 1959 classic &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/0262620014/ref=as_li_ss_tl?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;camp=1634&amp;amp;creative=19450&amp;amp;creativeASIN=0262620014&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;tag=dtse-21&quot;&gt;The Image of the City&lt;/a&gt;. In it, Lynch investigates how to design cities that are conducive to wayfinding, a term coined in the opening pages of the book. While urban planners are the intended audience of the book, the parallels with information interaction are staggering. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Not only is the city an object which is perceived (and perhaps enjoyed) by millions of people of widely diverse class and character, but it is the product of many builders who are constantly modifying the structure for reasons of their own. While it may be stable in general outlines for some time, it is ever changing in detail. Only partial control can be exercised over its growth and form. There is no final result, only a continuous succession of phases.”— Kevin Lynch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;environmental-images&quot;&gt;Environmental Images&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book stresses the importance of the “imageability” of a city, a quality that helps people build rich environmental images of their surroundings. The concept is very closely related mental models in user-centered design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We must consider not just the city as a thing in itself, but the city being perceived by its inhabitants.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In the process of way-finding, the strategic link is the environmental image, the generalized mental picture of the exterior physical world that is held by an individual.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A good environmental image gives its possessor an important sense of emotional security. He can establish an harmonious relationship between himself and the outside world. This is the obverse of the fear that comes with disorientation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-adaptable-image&quot;&gt;The Adaptable Image&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lynch’s environmental images are also highly individual. As with information environments, at any given instant in the city “there is more than the eye can see, more than the ear can hear.” A key aspect of wayfinding is rapidly building environmental images and applying them for localized problem solving, much as a user might do when searching for information online:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The observer himself should play an active role in perceiving the world and have a creative part in developing his image.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The observer—with great adaptability and in the light of his own purposes—selects, organises, and endows with meaning what he sees.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-metaphor-for-the-future&quot;&gt;A Metaphor for the Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the dominant metaphor of the web shifts from &lt;em&gt;the page&lt;/em&gt; to &lt;em&gt;spatial problem solving&lt;/em&gt;, I think there’s much we can learn about information interaction by studying how people find their way through the physical environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/05/from-the-page-to-the-city.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2013/02/05/from-the-page-to-the-city.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Investigating Cross-Channel Consistency</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-12-21/ecosystem.png&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;twothirds-width&quot; alt=&quot;The information architecture of discovery.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gestalt principle of consistency has served designers well for generations. But today, the designer’s canvas is expanding to include entire ecosystems where digital channels such as web and mobile must work in harmony with physical channels, from print media to the natural environment. As our remit expands, we must revisit the principles that have made us successful in the past, and reinterpret them for the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Merriam-Webster Dictionary&lt;/em&gt; defines consistency as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The agreement or harmony of parts or features to one another or a whole.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers, we have an intuitive understanding of how to achieve consistency. As we move from designing simple to increasingly complex systems, however, our intuition must be bolstered with a more systematic approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest that consistency can be divided into two dimensions, which I call the realm of consistency and the nature of consistency. First, we’ll investigate each of these dimensions; then we can consider how a systematic approach can be applied to the design of cross-channel experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/12/21/investigating-cross-channel-consistency.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/12/21/investigating-cross-channel-consistency.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience: The Book</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 18 Dec 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-12-18/map.jpg&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;The information architecture of discovery.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember the &lt;a href=&quot;http://dir.yahoo.com&quot;&gt;Yahoo! Directory&lt;/a&gt;? It was a hand-built taxonomy that allowed users to browse and discover Internet resources. By categorizing sites by topic and location, it became the definitive map of the World Wide Web. But at the turn of the millennium, Yahoo! transformed itself from a directory into a search engine. The task of organising so many disparate items into a single coherent structure had simply become too overwhelming. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;search-is-ubiquitous&quot;&gt;Search is ubiquitous&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a decade later, this story is all too familiar. Online stores sell hundreds of thousands of items, social networks host millions of users, and Flickr hosts billions of photos. Navigation is no longer the future: search is the key to sense-making in the digital universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet despite the growing influence of search on our daily lives, relatively few non-academic books have been published on the topic. While there are dozens of titles about designing web navigation, those on designing search can be counted on the fingers of one hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;That’s why Tony Russell-Rose and I set out to write &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designingthesearchexperience.com&quot;&gt;Designing the Search Experience&lt;/a&gt;: the Information Architecture of Discovery&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-book-for-a-new-era&quot;&gt;A new book for a new era&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the last year and half we have been researching, drafting and editing; striving to transform our ideas and insights into a coherent narrative. To help maintain our focus we established three guiding principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrated&lt;/strong&gt;: theoretical frameworks for human information seeking should be tightly integrated with practical design solutions, helping readers understand what, why, and how.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holistic&lt;/strong&gt;: individual design patterns should be related to the overall user experience, and search itself re-framed within the broader context of analysis and discovery-oriented problem solving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Readable&lt;/strong&gt;: The tone of voice should be informal and approachable, and the narrative driven by examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://designingthesearchexperience.com&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-12-18/cover.jpg&quot; width=&quot;382&quot; class=&quot;onethirds-width&quot; alt=&quot;The information architecture of discovery.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thank-you&quot;&gt;Thank You&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we haven’t worked alone. In particular, we’d like to thank &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cennydd.co.uk&quot;&gt;Cennydd Bowles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://experiencinginformation.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;James Kalbach&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.nott.ac.uk/~mlw/&quot;&gt;Max Wilson&lt;/a&gt; for their heroic efforts in reviewing every chapter and providing invaluable feedback all along the way. We are greatly in their debt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also very appreciative to those who contributed essays to the book: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucl.ac.uk/uclic/people/a_blandford&quot;&gt;Ann Blandford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/karenchurch&quot;&gt;Karen Church&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://everythingiknow.squarespace.com&quot;&gt;Rory Hamilton&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://experiencinginformation.wordpress.com&quot;&gt;James Kalbach&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joelamantia.com&quot;&gt;Joe Lamantia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.designcaffeine.com&quot;&gt;Greg Nudelman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://louisrosenfeld.com/home/&quot;&gt;Louis Rosenfeld&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cis.strath.ac.uk/cis/staff/index.php?uid=52833&quot;&gt;Ian Ruthven&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://thenoisychannel.com&quot;&gt;Daniel Tunkelang&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intranetfocus.com/about/martin-white&quot;&gt;Martin White&lt;/a&gt;. They have all enriched the book with their expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to Meg Dunkerley, Heather Scherer, Andrea Dierna, Rachel Roumeliotis, and the rest of the Morgan Kaufmann team for their ongoing support. We are proud of what we’ve achieved together. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-it-out&quot;&gt;Check it out&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Designing the Search Experience&lt;/em&gt; is finally available in print. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingthesearchexperience.com&quot;&gt;find more details&lt;/a&gt; at the associated website, along with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://designingthesearchexperience.com/downloads/dtse-chapter2.pdf&quot;&gt;free sample chapter&lt;/a&gt;. Tony and I are pleased with the result—we hope you will be too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/12/18/designing-the-search-experience-book.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/12/18/designing-the-search-experience-book.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Cross-Channel Experiences</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;As people interact with information across a growing number channels both digital (such as computers, tablets, phones) and physical (from print to the built environment), a new form of design is becoming increasingly important. The most successful businesses of today and tomorrow will be those who can provide cohesive experiences to their customers across the numerous channels that those customers demand. While designers are ideally suited to deliver on this challenge, we must expand our mindset and develop new tools in order to succeed. 
This talk aims to achieve just that. You will learn about three characteristics of cohesive cross-channel experiences—division of labour, consistency, and continuity—and how to put those principles into practice using two design methods: the cross-channel blueprint and the experience map.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2012/11/08/designing-cross-channel-experiences.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2012/11/08/designing-cross-channel-experiences.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Future of Information</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Web pages are dead. The future of information—and how people interact with it—is undergoing a profound metamorphosis. Our eulogy must begin long before web pages were conceived. Before the Internet, there was the written word; the book was the preeminent artefact for disseminating and assimilating information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scroll-and-the-table-of-contents&quot;&gt;The Scroll and the Table of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In their early form, books were scrawled on scrolls. Scarcely a format conducive for rapidly jumping from place to place, scrolls were intended to be read linearly. Despite this constraint, the first tables of contents were developed for scroll manuscripts. In the first century A.D., for instance, Pliny the Elder preceded his 37-volume &lt;em&gt;Natural History&lt;/em&gt; with a detailed table of contents (Forsythe, 2012). Such tables distilled the contents of a work into a taxonomy of volumes, sections, and chapters so that a reader would not have to scroll through the entire work to find their topic of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-printing-press-and-the-index&quot;&gt;The Printing Press and the Index&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the advent of the printing press, however, that the taxonomical organisation of the book—the table of contents—was augmented with a secondary organisational scheme: the index (Wellisch, 1991). Having transformed leafless, handwritten scrolls into mass-market books with numbered pages, the printing press made it practical to create, replicate, and use an alphabetised index of topics. If the reader could not locate their topic of choice in the table of contents, they could look it up in the much more granular index and jump directly to the relevant page in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-early-internet-and-the-web-page&quot;&gt;The Early Internet and the Web Page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early World Wide Web scarcely advanced this paradigm. The book had become the website, the table of contents had become the website’s navigation, and book pages had simply become web pages. Like the book that preceded it, the early website was a top-down construction: a rigid taxonomy of pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, we quickly realised that these one-size-fits-all taxonomies, well, did not always fit everyone’s needs. To fix the problem, we bolted-on inferior site search tools and prepared A-Z indexes of topics. In other words, we did more or less the same thing that we’d been doing for the last five centuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-faceted-search&quot;&gt;The Rise of Faceted Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But things were about to change. Half a century earlier, an Indian librarian had proposed a new way of organising information. Rather than use a rigid taxonomy, S. R. Ranganathan suggested that information should be categorised using multiple characteristics, what we now call “facets” (Tunkelang, 2009). By the early 2000s, information retrieval systems were beginning to augment keyword searches with faceted navigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this revolutionary development, a person could finally access information not just through someone else’s top-down taxonomy or A-Z index, but by simply interacting with the facets that match their own mental model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pageless-future&quot;&gt;The Pageless Future&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there’s a problem. Because faceted navigation was developed as an extension of search—and search itself was added to websites to provide an alternative to traditional web navigation—these two forms of navigation often still share an awkward co-existence. Users must choose whether to follow the website’s table of contents, or whether to turn to the faceted index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the future, this distinction will disappear. There is no need for a user to perform a keyword search in order to access faceted navigation; and there is nothing that traditional navigation accomplishes which faceted navigation does not also achieve. In other words, the table of contents and the index are destined to merge into one, faceted experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed, we can see this future unfolding before us. When we use the Web to shop, pick out recipes, look for a house, find a job, or choose a film to watch, we already engage in faceted, pageless interactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-happy-ending&quot;&gt;A Happy Ending&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this faceted future, there are no pages. The story that began millennia ago is finally coming to fruition: information is being liberated from the page—and the taxonomies, the fixed tables of contents—which bound them to a rigid existence. And users, unconstrained by foreign hierarchies, are finally free to explore information in its purest form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;references&quot;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forsythe, G. (2012). History of Information Retrieval. Retrieved from http://www.asindexing.org/i4a/pages/index.cfm?pageID=3300 on Oct 29, 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wellisch, H. (1991). Indexing from A to Z. Hw Wilson Co.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tunkelang, D. (2009). Faceted Search. Synthesis Lectures on Information Concepts, Retrieval, and Services. Morgan &amp;amp; Claypool. p7.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/11/01/the-future-of-information.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/11/01/the-future-of-information.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Mobile Search</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 2010 there were more computers manufactured than mobile devices—but just barely. Starting in 2011, the number of smartphones and tablets began outpacing the number laptops and desktops being sold. While these devices are being purchased primarily by consumers rather than corporate IT departments, there’s a growing trend to Bring Your Own Device (BYOD) to work. Mobile devices are becoming ubiquitous—both at home and at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Search has long been the de facto method for interacting with information, and mobile devices are no different. Yet the temptation to replicate desktop-oriented user interface conventions on mobile devices is far from ideal. That’s why designing mobile search is an important topic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/05/18/designing-mobile-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/05/18/designing-mobile-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Mobile Search</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Presented in New York at the Enterprise Search Summit and the NY Enterprise Search meetup.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2012/05/16/designing-mobile-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2012/05/16/designing-mobile-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Consistency, Part 3: Cross-Channel Guidelines</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/08/on-consistency-three-levels.html&quot;&gt;Part 1&lt;/a&gt; I identified three &lt;em&gt;levels&lt;/em&gt; of consistency: internal, local, and external (analogous to creature, habitat, and ecosystem). In &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/09/on-consistency-four-types.html&quot;&gt;Part 2&lt;/a&gt; I discussed four &lt;em&gt;types&lt;/em&gt; of consistency: functional, behavioral, organizational, and aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this third and final installment, I’d like to offer some very basic guidelines for appropriately aligning consistency across the multiple channels of an ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;functional&quot;&gt;Functional&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The function of a channel should be optimized for its own comparative advantage; in other words, what it has the potential of doing better than any other channel in the ecosystem. In this way, its function need not be externally &lt;em&gt;consistent&lt;/em&gt;, as much as it should be &lt;em&gt;complimentary&lt;/em&gt; to the rest of the ecosystem, yet internally consistent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;behavioral&quot;&gt;Behavioral&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a behavioral tension between the local habitat—be it website conventions or operating system patterns—and the process flows of the ecosystem. Great effort should be exerted to reconcile these differences. Where perfect integration isn’t possible, erring on the side of local consistency is often the more conciliatory approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;organizational&quot;&gt;Organizational&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizational consistency should almost always favor the external ecosystem over the local or internal. Using a consistent organizational scheme across all channels of the ecosystem is one of the most important factors in delivering a seamless cross-channel experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;aesthetic&quot;&gt;Aesthetic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aesthetics has major implications across all three levels. It should certainly maintain internal consistency. Yet there is again a tension between the local habitat and external ecosystem that must be carefully negotiated. While the aspects of the look and feel that involve branding, such as color, should be consistent with the ecosystem, the overriding style of the user interface should match its local habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/21/on-consistency-part-3-guidelines-cross-channel-consistency.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/21/on-consistency-part-3-guidelines-cross-channel-consistency.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Experience Map</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Last month when I blogged about the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/02/21/cross-channel-ia-blueprint.html&quot;&gt;cross-channel blueprint&lt;/a&gt; as a tool for planning the tasks and channels of an ecosystem, several people commented that it failed to fully account for user. Indeed, those comments helped me realize that the cross-channel blueprint is itself a &lt;em&gt;system-oriented&lt;/em&gt; diagram—useful  as a planning tool and for the concise overview it provides—but that it must be paired with a &lt;em&gt;user-centered&lt;/em&gt; perspective. One such tool is an obvious companion: the experience map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-an-experience-map&quot;&gt;What is an experience map?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes called a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.servicedesigntools.org/tools/8&quot;&gt;customer journey map&lt;/a&gt; (a label which is &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/07/employees-are-customers-too.html&quot;&gt;unnecessarily narrow&lt;/a&gt;), the experience map is a tool born out of service design. It visually represents not only a user’s interactions with the system, but is also concerned with the emotional state of the user throughout the entire process. Experience maps help everyone involved put themselves in the user’s shoes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike the cross-channel blueprint that can be created in front of a whiteboard &lt;em&gt;ex nihilo&lt;/em&gt;, experience maps rely on user research. Both quantitative measures such as log data and survey results, and particularly qualitative techniques such as field studies should be used to shape an accurate map of the user’s experience. In addition, the experience map can focus either on a group of users—portraying their behavior and attitudes in aggregate—or on an individual user, in which case an accompanying persona is valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience maps come in many different forms. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.adaptivepath.com/ideas/the-anatomy-of-an-experience-map&quot;&gt;Chris Risdon&lt;/a&gt; of Adaptive Path uses five dimensions—the lens, the journey model, qualitative insight, quantitative information, and takeaways; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mycustomer.com/topic/customer-intelligence/customer-journey-mapping/105167&quot;&gt;Arne van Oosterom&lt;/a&gt; describes ten—including the customer journey, moments of truth, and the emotional journey; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://experiencinginformation.wordpress.com/2010/05/10/customer-journey-mapping-resources-on-the-web/&quot;&gt;James Kalbach&lt;/a&gt; has compiled a long list of related resources, each with a slightly different take on the tool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-an-experience-map&quot;&gt;Creating an experience map&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its many varieties, creating a basic experience map involves these three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outline the user’s journey&lt;/strong&gt;. Start by creating a list of all the occurrences that constitute the user’s experience not just within the ecosystem, but throughout their entire journey from beginning to end. These occurrences can then be arranged horizontally to form a timeline.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List the channel and goal&lt;/strong&gt; for each step of the user’s journey. Channel refers to the medium through which the action is performed. Goal describes the underlying motivation for performing the action. These components should be consistent with the two dimensions of the cross-channel blueprint.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Describe the user’s emotion&lt;/strong&gt; and rate their satisfaction for every step of the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once these basic components have been created, additional analysis can be added as needed. Here’s an example experience map I’ve created following these steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;full-width&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-03-19/experience-map.png&quot; width=&quot;2933&quot; height=&quot;480&quot; alt=&quot;An example experience map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the experience map is an effective tool for understanding how users interact with an ecosystem, and is an ideal companion to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/02/21/cross-channel-ia-blueprint.html&quot;&gt;cross-channel blueprint&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/19/the-experience-map.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/19/the-experience-map.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Optimization: The Division of Labor</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In the opening pages of &lt;em&gt;The Wealth of Nations&lt;/em&gt;, Adam Smith demonstrates the power of the division of labor through the example of a pin factory. At that time, the process for manufacturing sewing pins consisted of about 18 operations, such as drawing out the wire, straightening it, cutting it, pointing it, sanding it, and so on. Each tasks was sufficiently involved, Smith maintained, that a single individual could perhaps “make one pin in a day, and certainly could not make twenty.” Yet when each operation was distributed to a tradesmen specialized in that task, the team “could make amongst them upwards of 48,000 pins in a day.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;division-of-labor-and-the-ipod&quot;&gt;Division of labor and the iPod&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs made a similar, though less profound realization around the turn of the millennium: he saw the computer acting as the central hub for digital devices. This strategy would allow both the computer and the device to play to their respective strengths, just as the specialized tradesmen at the pin factory were able to do. Biographer Walter Isaacson summarizes Jobs’ thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A lot of the functions that the devices tried to do, such as editing the video or the pictures, they did poorly because they had small screens and could not easily accommodate menus filled with lots of functions. Computers could handle that more easily.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This insight most notably led to Apple’s introduction of the iPod. Rather than designing the portable music player to be self-sufficient, as their competitors had done, the iPod was designed as part of a symbiotic ecosystem. The iPod was freed to do what it did best—play music—while the computer handled the more complex task of managing the music collection, and the iTunes store enabled users to acquire new songs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-principle-of-optimization&quot;&gt;The principle of optimization&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The division of labor between the iPod, iTunes, and Mac enabled the three to collectively achieve more than they could have on their own. This is the principle of &lt;em&gt;optimization&lt;/em&gt; at work. Each channel within the ecosystem should focus on what it does best. Put another way, each component should be optimized for its unique &lt;em&gt;affordances&lt;/em&gt;, that is, the inherent characteristics of an object that communicate its purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Each component should be optimized for its unique affordances.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small handheld device, for instance, lends itself to being used on the go and for short bursts of time; a keyboard-equipped desktop computer, on the other hand, affords more focused attention and a greater amount of data entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By optimizing each element of the ecosystem, we can achieve cross-channel experiences that truly empower users in unprecedented ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/12/on-optimization-the-division-of-labor.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/12/on-optimization-the-division-of-labor.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Consistency, Part 2: Four Types</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 09 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/08/on-consistency-three-levels.html&quot;&gt;part 1&lt;/a&gt; I outlined three common &lt;em&gt;levels&lt;/em&gt; of consistency: internal, local, and external (analogous to creature, habitat, ecosystem). Here I’d like to turn our attention to a second dimension: &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While &lt;em&gt;level&lt;/em&gt; answers the question, “Is object A similar to object B?”, &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt; is concerned with: “&lt;em&gt;In what way&lt;/em&gt; is object A similar with object B?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-types-of-consistency&quot;&gt;Four types of consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to slice cakes and skin cats, yet these four types of consistency seem most relevant to cross-channel design:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Function&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Purpose&lt;/em&gt;. The purpose of a print catalog is to encourage serendipitous discovery. The purpose of a retailer’s website is to facilitate both discovery and the lookup of known items.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavior&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;How it works&lt;/em&gt;. The interaction design. The process flow involved in completing a task.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organization&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;How it’s organized&lt;/em&gt;. The taxonomy driving both digital and physical wayfinding. For instance, the way in which products are organized in stores of both the online and brick-and-mortar sort.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aesthetics&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;em&gt;How it looks&lt;/em&gt;. The visual style.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-the-pieces-together&quot;&gt;Putting the pieces together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking consistency down into its component parts is more than just a thought exercise. A careful consideration of the levels and types of consistency is central to designing seamless cross-channel experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, it’s useful to consider which levels and types of consistency should take precedence over others. A retailer creating an iPhone application, for instance, might decide that the &lt;em&gt;behavior&lt;/em&gt; should be consistent with its &lt;em&gt;local&lt;/em&gt; habitat (in this case, other iPhone apps), whereas the &lt;em&gt;organization&lt;/em&gt; scheme should match that of the &lt;em&gt;external&lt;/em&gt; ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://www.tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-03-09/consistency-strategy.jpg&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;A consistency diagram&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A consistency diagram.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/09/on-consistency-four-types.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/09/on-consistency-four-types.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>On Consistency, Part 1: Three Levels</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Consistency is lauded as a staple ingredient of every good user experience; a fundamental principle of interaction design; a golden rule of the user interface. Yet it’s a heuristic that’s sometimes misunderstood and often oversimplified. Consistency is more complex than intuition would lead us to believe, rife with tension and competing forces, and often seemingly contradictory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;consistent-with-what&quot;&gt;Consistent with what?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often judge “that’s consistent” or “that’s inconsistent” without specifying the object of our comparison. Yet something may be both consistent and inconsistent &lt;em&gt;at the same time&lt;/em&gt;. The question is: consistent with what?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To date, the components of consistency have most often been described as internal, external, functional, and aesthetic (see &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Universal-Principles-Design-Usability-Perception/dp/1592530079&quot;&gt;Universal Principles of Design&lt;/a&gt;). I’d like to focus on just the first two in this post. Internal and external occupy two polarities of a single continuum that we can call the &lt;em&gt;level&lt;/em&gt; of consistency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-03-08/continuum.jpg&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;Three levels: internal, local, external&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The levels of consistency continuum.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;three-levels-of-consistency&quot;&gt;Three levels of consistency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the traditional continuum is useful, the points along that continuum deserve further exploration. In particular, we need to account for how consistency affects cross-channel experiences. In that light, I suggest that three points—not two—should underpin our thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;creature&lt;/em&gt; itself. A specific website, application, or experience in isolation from all others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local&lt;/strong&gt;. The immediate &lt;em&gt;habitat&lt;/em&gt; in which a website, application, or experience coexists. It could be the web as a whole or a device’s operating system, for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;External&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;ecosystem&lt;/em&gt; encompassing the habitats in which the various websites, applications, and experiences reside.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-03-08/ecosystem.jpg&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;Three levels: internal, local, external&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The three levels can be thought of in ecological terms: the creature, the habitat, and the ecosystem.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-be-clear&quot;&gt;Let’s be clear&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this vantage point we can rationalize how some forms of consistency should trump others. For instance, certain OS conventions—such as the visual style for buttons—should usually take precedence over ecosystem-wide consistency; the local application, on the other hand, should most often be subservient to ensuring a seamless experience across the ecosystem as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope to discuss a second dimension of consistency in a future post: &lt;em&gt;type&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/08/on-consistency-three-levels.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/08/on-consistency-three-levels.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>UX, CX, and Service Design: Employees Are Customers Too</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;User experience design is growing up. We’ve finally realized that UX is less about creating end-all-be-all websites, and more about designing cross-channel ecosystems that encompass both the digital and physical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;multi-disciplinary-is-good&quot;&gt;Multi-disciplinary is Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of this journey, we’ve wisely been reaching out to other disciplines for inspiration. &lt;em&gt;Service design&lt;/em&gt; has taught us to consider customer journeys from touchpoint to touchpoint across multiple channels. &lt;em&gt;Customer experience design&lt;/em&gt; has encouraged us to put our business hats on and align user experience with business strategy. Both of these disciplines exert a positive influence on user experience design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;customers-arent-the-only-users&quot;&gt;Customers aren’t the only users&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet there is one flaw in all of this. As we’ve been striving towards cross-channel design, mapping customer journeys, and dwelling on customer experience, our thinking has been invariably focused on just that: &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt;. This is unsurprising—retailers with both online and brick-and-mortar presences are a natural birthplace for such innovation. Yet we must avoid assuming that strategic, cross-channel experiences belong exclusively to the consumer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We must avoid assuming that strategic, cross-channel experiences belong exclusively to the consumer.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;meet-mr-employee&quot;&gt;Meet Mr. Employee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, seamless cross-channel experiences are vital to &lt;em&gt;employees&lt;/em&gt; as well. Imagine a doctor moving between his private office, the clinic hallway, and the patient’s consulting room. Or an engineer moving from the design lab, to the assembly room, to the testing facility. Or a sales person rarely at her desk who stops off at coffee shops between sales calls. Understanding the user’s journey and designing effective cross-channel experiences is just as important for employees as it is for customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-point&quot;&gt;My point?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not that we have nothing to learn from service design or customer experience design, quite the contrary. However, let’s not turn UX design into a discipline focused solely on &lt;em&gt;customers&lt;/em&gt;; let’s keep designing for &lt;em&gt;users&lt;/em&gt; of all sorts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/07/employees-are-customers-too.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/03/07/employees-are-customers-too.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cross-Channel Blueprints: A tool for modern IA</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of information architecture is undergoing a tectonic shift away from creating individual websites and towards designing cross-channel experiences that span both the digital—from desktop to mobile—and the physical—from print to storefront. While the information architect’s skillset is well-suited for this new challenge, our existing tools are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;service-blueprints-arent-exactly-what-we-need&quot;&gt;Service blueprints aren’t exactly what we need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imported from the field of service design, G. Lynn Shostack’s &lt;em&gt;service blueprint&lt;/em&gt; is often suggested as a tool for cross-channel planning. Yet it’s not a perfect fit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Too process-oriented&lt;/strong&gt;. Service blueprints present customer actions sequentially. While desirable for planning specific flows (such as a checkout process), it’s obstructive when trying to outline a comprehensive strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal attention to channels&lt;/strong&gt;. Service blueprints document the “physical evidence” associated with each action, but fail to account for how a single action might be performed on multiple channels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meant for a different purpose&lt;/strong&gt;. With their lines of interaction, visibility, and internal visibility, service blueprints simply weren’t intended to be used for planning cross-channel information architecture &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-02-21/service-blueprint-brandonschauer.png&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;A service blueprint by Brandon Schauer&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A service blueprint created by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/brandonschauer/3363169836/&quot;&gt;Brandon Schauer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-we-need-then&quot;&gt;What do we need, then?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before brainstorming solutions, we should clarify the problem. Andrea Resmini and Lucas Rosati have discussed five principles for designing successful cross-channel experiences; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/mobile/morville/crosschannel-strategy&quot;&gt;Peter Morville&lt;/a&gt; advocates six; to me, these three seem the most fundamental:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consistent.&lt;/strong&gt; Each channel should enable users to perform a given task in a like manner. For instance, a bank customer experienced in paying bills on the web should find the corresponding smartphone bill-paying facility familiar, even on first use.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimized.&lt;/strong&gt; Each channel should play to its strengths. Desktop applications are optimized for large screens; mobile apps for small ones. Optimization is in tension with consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous.&lt;/strong&gt; Each channel must be aware of all the others. Add a bicycle helmet to your shopping cart on the Web, and it should appear in the cart on your phone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-starting-point&quot;&gt;A starting point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would a tool that aimed to facilitate consistent, optimized, continuous cross-channel planning look like? In &lt;a href=&quot;http://pervasiveia.com/&quot;&gt;Pervasive Information Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, Resmini and Rosati presented their CHU cube which places &lt;em&gt;tasks&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;channels&lt;/em&gt; each on their own axes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-02-21/chu-cube.jpg&quot; width=&quot;475&quot; class=&quot;twothirds-width&quot; alt=&quot;The CHU Cube&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://pervasiveia.com/&quot;&gt;Resmini and Rosati’s&lt;/a&gt; CHU cube plots channels, heuristics, and tasks using three dimensions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ammendment: &lt;em&gt;After publishing this post, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/#!/lowresolution&quot;&gt;Gianluca Brugnoli&lt;/a&gt; of Frog Design pointed out its resemblence to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.servicedesigntools.org/tools/108&quot;&gt;Touchpoints Matrix&lt;/a&gt; he himself developed in 2009. I hadn’t come across this tool before, but the similarity is striking.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-02-21/touchpoints-matrix.png&quot; width=&quot;712&quot; class=&quot;normal-width&quot; alt=&quot;The Touchpoints Matrix by Gianluca Brugnoli&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Touchpoints Matrix by Gianluca Brugnoli&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;building-on-the-foundation&quot;&gt;Building on the foundation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juxtaposing tasks and channels is a useful starting point, though the CHUbe’s multidimensional layers make it a bit unwieldy. For our diagram, let’s do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify user tasks&lt;/strong&gt;—these become the X-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;List channels&lt;/strong&gt;—these become the Y-axis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritize and describe each per-channel task&lt;/strong&gt;—these are the table cells&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify shared components&lt;/strong&gt;—these are listed in a bottom row&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-02-21/cross-channel-blueprint.png&quot; width=&quot;1030&quot; class=&quot;full-width&quot; alt=&quot;A Cross-Channel Blueprint&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I call this a &lt;em&gt;cross-channel blueprint&lt;/em&gt;. The exercise can be performed by a lone designer or collaboratively with sticky notes or in front of a whiteboard. It brings about:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A global view of important user tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The possible channels through which users might attempt those tasks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A set of task priorities for each channel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A set of channel priorities for each task&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An overview of which components need to be shared across channels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-do-you-think&quot;&gt;What do you think?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is but a first attempt at a developing a tool suitable for the new era of cross-channel information architecture. As such, it needs practice, iteration, and experimentation. If you’ve been working in this space, please chime in with how the cross-channel blueprint jives with your own experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;See my article &lt;a href=&quot;http://uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2011/10/the-rise-of-cross-channel-ux-design.php&quot;&gt;The Rise of Cross-Channel UX Design&lt;/a&gt; on UX Matters for related reading. You can also &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/tylertate&quot;&gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/02/21/cross-channel-ia-blueprint.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/02/21/cross-channel-ia-blueprint.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Three Circles of Collaborative Search</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Search often appears personal, introspective, and private; an activity of the individual in isolation. In fact, most researchers depict search as a single-user activity. Yet a 2008 survey found that over half of respondents self-reported having co-operated with other people to search the web, while an impressive 97.1% went on to indicate at least one form of collaborative search activity in which they had engaged (Morris, 2008). It’s safe to say that collaboration is pervasive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet collaborative search is a broad term, encompassing explicit cooperation with others during information seeking, enlisting help from one’s social groups, and implicit collaboration with strangers. We must attain a holistic view of collaboration in order to design socially-aware search applications that support collaboration. I believe that holistic view can be found in a three-circle model: the inner circle, intermediate social circles, and the outer circle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/23/three-circles-of-collaborative-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/23/three-circles-of-collaborative-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Design Principles for Mobile Search</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Apple’s iOS Human Interface Guidelines, Google’s Android Design Guidlines, and others such as Luke Wroblewski’s Mobile First book provide valuable guidance for designing general mobile applications. Yet there are a number of design principles unique to crafting mobile search experiences in particular. Namely: prioritizing content over controls, providing answers over results, being sensitive to context, and ensuring cross-channel continuity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/13/design-principles-mobile-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/13/design-principles-mobile-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Coping with Sub-pixel Rounding in IE</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;An old, ugly problem still plagues fluid layouts: sub-pixel rounding. You’ve experienced this nasty issue when elements within your percentage-based layout unexpectedly wrap to the next line in Internet Explorer, or aren’t flush with the right-hand edge in Safari and Chrome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The culprit? How percentages are rounded into pixel values by the browser. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://ejohn.org/blog/sub-pixel-problems-in-css/&quot;&gt;John Resig documented&lt;/a&gt; in 2008, browsers have adopted different rounding strategies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Webkit and Opera always round down, FireFox and Internet Explorer 8 and 9 round some numbers up, others down, and IE6 &amp;amp; IE7 always round up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is the output of this &lt;a href=&quot;http://tylertate.github.com/subpixel-rounding/examples/four/four.html&quot;&gt;example page&lt;/a&gt; in the major browsers. I’ve extended John Resig’s original demonstration by testing 4 columns, each 25% wide, within three differently sized containers: 49px, 50px, and 51px. The number shown below each container is the theoretical pixel width of one of the columns (e.g. 50px * .25 = 12.5).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-01-05/browser-subpixel-rounding.png&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; max-width: 620px;&quot; alt=&quot;The sub-pixel rounding problem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll notice that in Webkit and Opera, which use the rounding-down strategy, there is space leftover. FireFox, IE8, and IE9, on other hand, vary the widths of the boxes so that, in total, they occupy all of the available space. &lt;strong&gt;But here’s the catch:&lt;/strong&gt; when the floating decimal is .5 or greater, our old friends IE6 and 7 stupidly &lt;strong&gt;round up&lt;/strong&gt;, forcing the final column in our example to wrap to the next line since the four columns become collectively wider than their parent container. Facepalm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is certainly not a new problem; it’s been the source of head-to-wall bashing for over a decade. Yet it’s an important problem to understand and address in the modern era of fluid, responsive layouts. While it’s true that the problem will mostly go away when IE6 and 7 support is no longer necessary, many of us need a solution now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-formula&quot;&gt;The formula&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there’s no silver bullet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The only way to prevent layouts from breaking in IE6/7 is to fractionally reduce the percentages so that they add up to just under 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past this has meant fiddling down the numbers until the elements stop wrapping, an inexact and error-prone art. There is, however, an exact science to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The objective is simply to get IE to round numbers down, not up. In the example above, we want 12.5px, 12.75px, or even 12.99px, to be rounded down to 12px, just like it would be in WebKit. The solution is straightforward in principle: just subtract half a pixel. 12.99px would then become 12.49px, and—since the floating decimal is less than .5—IE would round down to the nearest integer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the tricky bit is getting from pixels back to percentages. What percentage do we need to subtract in order to produce a half-pixel reduction in the computed pixel value? The answer: &lt;strong&gt;it depends on the pixel width of the parent container&lt;/strong&gt;. Here’s the formula:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;O.5 / containerWidth = correctionLevel
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ContainerWidth&lt;/code&gt; is the pixel width of the container, while &lt;code&gt;correctionLevel&lt;/code&gt; represents the percentage that needs to be subtracted in order for IE to round down to the nearest pixel. Thus for our 50px container above, the &lt;code&gt;correctionLevel&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;0.5 / 50 = 0.01&lt;/code&gt;, or 1%. That means instead of the four columns each being 25%, they would need to be 24% (25 - 1). With that corretion applied, the columns would each be computed as 12px rather than 12.5px, and our layout will display correctly, as shown below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://tylertate.com/resources/images/2012-01-05/browser-subpixel-rounding-corrected.png&quot; width=&quot;620&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%; max-width: 620px;&quot; alt=&quot;Sub-pixel rounding with the correction formula applied&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the whole point of using percentages, I hear you saying, is to be pixel-independent. If I have to specify the container’s pixel width, doesn’t that defeat the purpose of using percentages in the first place? It’s painfully inconvenient, to be sure, but the very fact that you’re reading this is evidence enough that we must work around this problem somehow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are two strategies for applying this correction formula.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-it-yourself-calculations&quot;&gt;Do-it-yourself calculations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can quickly apply the above formula to your existing fluid layouts to fix the sub-pixel rounding issue in IE6 and 7 without adversely affecting other browsers. First, lets assume you have constructed a percentage-based layout that has a set minimum width of &lt;strong&gt;720px&lt;/strong&gt;. Using this number as our baseline &lt;code&gt;containerWidth&lt;/code&gt;, our formula tells us that the correctionLevel is &lt;strong&gt;.0694%&lt;/strong&gt;. Whenever a percentage is used as the value of a width, padding, border, or margin declaration, we’ll use the star hack to add IE6/7-specific declarations which subtract .0694% from the original value. Here’s a simplistic example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section#sidebar {
  width: 25%;
  *width: 24.93%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;css-frameworks&quot;&gt;CSS frameworks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using a CSS framework such as &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesscss.org/&quot;&gt;LESS.js&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://sass-lang.com&quot;&gt;SaSS&lt;/a&gt;, you can rely on their mathematic operations to save you from having to crunching all the numbers by hand. The LESS/SaSS code below would be compiled to the same output as in the example above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;section#sidebar {
  width: 25%;
  *width: 25%-0.0694%;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Updated January 11, 2012.&lt;/em&gt; The newly-released version 1.2 of &lt;a href=&quot;http://Semantic.gs&quot;&gt;The Semantic Grid System&lt;/a&gt;—which uses the power of CSS frameworks to elegantly power fixed, fluid, and responsive layouts—incorporates the above formula. It allows you to specify the minimum width of your layout, from which it then derives the correction level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;@min-width: 960;
@correction: 0.5 / @min-width * 100 * 1%;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then subtracts the correction level from the IE-specific width and margin declarations of each column in the layout:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;width: @computedWidth;
margin: 0 @computedMargin;

*width: @computedWidth-@correction;
*margin: 0 @computedMargin-@correction;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-last-word&quot;&gt;The last word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have it: a predictable formula for correcting the sub-pixel rounding problem in Internet Explorer 6 and 7. It’s just one more reason we can all rejoice when IE6 and 7 go the way of the grave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/05/subpixel-rounding.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2012/01/05/subpixel-rounding.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Mobile Information Needs</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Mobile information needs can be assed by two criteria: scope and type. Scope describes the sophistication of the information need, the degree of higher-level thinking it involves, and the time commitment required to satisfy it. The lookup, learn, and investigate elements of scope are derived from Gary Marchionini’s work on exploratory search, while the casual component has been more recently advocated by Max Wilson and others.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/12/06/mobile-information-needs.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/12/06/mobile-information-needs.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing Mobile Search</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/11/22/designing-mobile-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/11/22/designing-mobile-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Rise of Cross-Channel UX Design</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;A few Saturdays ago, I was walking around Greenwich in southeast London when I decided to peruse the local bookshop. Drawn to a display titled “Utopias and Dystopias,” I noticed the book A Brave New World sitting beside George Orwell’s 1984, which I had read and remembered enjoying. Curious about the association between the two, I picked up A Brave New World and glanced over the back cover. I then pulled out my phone and searched Google to see what others were saying about the book and noted that it is often considered one of the top-100 novels of all time. My mind was settled: I wanted to read this book. But rather than walking, book in hand, to the checkout counter, I instead used my phone to navigate to Amazon’s Kindle Store, where I typed in the name of the book and used their 1-click ordering to purchase the book. Leaving the bookshop empty handed, I caught the next bus home. On the way home, I pulled out my tablet device and started reading page 1 of A Brave New World.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/17/cross-channel-ux-design.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/17/cross-channel-ux-design.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Search Analytics by Lou Rosenfeld</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The book is a very practical guide on how to exploit query logs to improve your company’s search experience. Lou outlines a collection of simple but potent techniques for analyzing search logs, spotting insightful patterns, and putting those insights to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/13/book-review-search-analytics.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/13/book-review-search-analytics.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From physical to digital to ubiquitous</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The invention of the printing press transformed the physical object that is the book from an artefact of human transcription to that of mass production. By 1500, just 40 years after Gutenberg’s invention, an estimated 150 to 200 million copies had rolled off the press; a century later, the by then pervasive technology led to the rise of a new medium: the newspaper. This was the era of information as physical object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More recently, mass adoption of the world wide web and the plethora of Internet-connected devices has led to digital information augmenting and, to a certain degree, displacing the physical. News was consumed online rather than on paper, new mediums of self expression arose from the blog to the social networks, and a new pair of shoes could be acquired without ever stepping foot in a store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are now on the cusp of yet another technological sea change. The pendulum which swung from physical to digital is swinging back to the real world, but this time, information is formless, contextual, and ubiquitous. In their book &lt;a href=&quot;http://pervasiveia.com/&quot;&gt;Pervasive Information Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, Andrea Resmini and Luca Rosati describe this brave new world of ubiquitous computing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Information is going everywhere. It is bleeding out of the Internet and out of personal computers, and it is being embedded into the real world. Mobile devices, networked resources, and real-time information systems are making our interactions with information constant and ubiquitous. Information is becoming pervasive.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future lies in cross-channel experiences. Interactions in which the technology fades to the background and the personal, physical, and social context of the present mediate the devices and methods with which we interact with information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You know the Hemingway line, “Write all the story, take out all the good lines, and see if it still works”? Well, I’m posting these simple thoughts here because I just deleted them from a longer piece, but still wanted them to see the light of day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/11/from-physical-to-digital-to-ubiquitous.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/10/11/from-physical-to-digital-to-ubiquitous.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/09/14/designing-the-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/09/14/designing-the-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Dao of Learning: How Content Strategy Supports Learning on the Web</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/09/06/the-dao-of-learning.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/09/06/the-dao-of-learning.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Semantic Grid System</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;CSS grid frameworks can make your life easier, but they’re not without their faults. Fortunately for us, modern techniques offer a new approach to constructing page layouts. But before getting to the solution, we must first understand the three seemingly insurmountable flaws currently affecting CSS grids.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/08/23/semantic-grid-system.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/08/23/semantic-grid-system.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cognitive Content Strategy</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/08/05/cognitive-content-strategy.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/08/05/cognitive-content-strategy.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The UX of Learning</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Think of the last time you ordered a book, booked a flight, or bought a car. How did you choose which book to read, where to go for vacation, or which car was best for you? You may have searched online, read reviews, or asked others for advice to help you make an informed decision. In a word, you learned. Learning is a complex process with distinct stages, each with corresponding tasks and emotions. Understanding how users learn can help us design experiences that support the user throughout the entire process. To design better learning experiences online, start by learning a thing or two about learning itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/07/26/ux-of-learning.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/07/26/ux-of-learning.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Learning Styles</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You and I are different. It’s obvious, but has a profound impact on fulfilling the needs of disparate users. Not only do you and I have different accents, hairstyles, and musical tastes, but even our cognitive processes — the very building blocks of being human — are substantially different. I recently wrote about individual differences in expertise and cognitive style, but there is a third dimension: learning style. Understanding how people learn is fundamental to delivering desirable content, a prerequisite of any good user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/06/16/learning-styles.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/06/16/learning-styles.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Holistic Search Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/05/25/designing-the-holistic-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/05/25/designing-the-holistic-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Cognitive Styles</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We pour over analytics, conduct ethnographic studies, and interview users in order to understand the demographics, goals, and tasks of the people using our product. We create personas, write scenarios, and list use cases. And so we should; understanding who our users are and what they want to achieve is foundational to our job as designers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how deep does our understanding of users actually go? Sure, we know their socio-economic bracket, what industry they work in, and the top few tasks they want to achieve on our website. But are there deeper, more innately personal characteristics at work? Can we figure out what really makes them tick?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For over a century, psychologists have been trying to account for the range of individual differences people exhibit when interacting with new information. At the heart of their research lie cognitive styles—the stable attitudes, preferences, and habitual strategies that determine how an individual processes information. Understanding cognitive styles will help us design better experiences for users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/05/12/cognitive-styles.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/05/12/cognitive-styles.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Lookup to Learning</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/21/from-lookup-to-learning.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/21/from-lookup-to-learning.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Novices Orienteer, Experts Teleport</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Would you rather take a photo using your phone, a point-and-shoot camera, or a digital SLR? How you answer this question is probably a good indicator of your photographic expertise. If you snap casual shots, your phone or a point-and-shoot camera will probably suffice. If you’re a professional photographer, on the other hand, you probably prefer using an SLR that gives you control over the focus, aperture, and exposure. Expertise significantly impacts how we seek information online. Just as novice and expert photographers prefer different tools, so novices and experts behave differently when searching for information. Understanding these differences will help us design better search interfaces for both groups of users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/search/ux/2011/04/20/novices-orienteer-experts-teleport.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/search/ux/2011/04/20/novices-orienteer-experts-teleport.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing a Modern CRM</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/19/designing-a-modern-crm.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/19/designing-a-modern-crm.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Lookup to Learning</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/05/from-lookup-to-learning.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/04/05/from-lookup-to-learning.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Search as a Flow Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;When was the last time that you were “in the zone”? Do you remember being so absorbed in an activity that you forgot about the outside world, time seemed to fade away, and you felt invigorated? Maybe you’re an avid tennis player and remember a rigorous game when you seemed on fire. Or perhaps you’re a musician and recall feeling as if the notes were flowing through your fingertips. Psychologist Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi calls this state of optimal experience flow. In his research, he found that musicians, composers, athletes, and even chess players all used the same words to explain their enjoyment. Csikszentmihalyi identified 8 elements that contribute to a flow experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/02/09/search-as-a-flow-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/02/09/search-as-a-flow-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Search as a Flow Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/02/08/search-as-a-flow-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/02/08/search-as-a-flow-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Review of Foodily’s Recipe Search</title>
				<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;This past week I discovered a new recipe search engine called Foodily. Both the interaction and the visual design are superb, and Foodily makes use of several novel patterns that I thought would be worth pointing out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/02/05/a-review-of-foodilys-recipe-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/02/05/a-review-of-foodilys-recipe-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Pattern to Component</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/02/01/from-pattern-to-component.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2011/02/01/from-pattern-to-component.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>From Pattern to Component</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2011 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;In 1899 the largest automobile producer in world, Benz &amp;amp; Cie, made a grand total of 572 cars. Few could afford such hand-built luxuries. But in 1908 Henry Ford began to mass-produce the Model T using an assembly line. By distilling the complex process of constructing an automobile into a distinct set of repeatable tasks, Ford reduced the time required to assemble a car down to just 93 minutes. By the 1920s, 10,000 cars were being produced every day, each with a price tag of just $290. Software, too, thrives on the transformation of abstract ideas into concrete, reusable components.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/01/05/from-pattern-to-component.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2011/01/05/from-pattern-to-component.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Dealing with Diverse Data</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/12/02/dealing-with-diverse-data.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/12/02/dealing-with-diverse-data.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Nutshell Launches in NYC</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been an exciting week for the Nutshell team. We’ve been in New York City officially launching the company in front of about 500 of our peers at the Future of Web Design conference. On Monday, Andy Fowler (our lead developer) and I went on stage at the end of the conference to make the big announcement. We shared some of the key tenets of our development strategy including cross-platform design, building the API first, and prototyping on paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/11/18/nutshell-launches-in-nyc.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/11/18/nutshell-launches-in-nyc.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Review of Simple and Usable by Giles Colborne</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve all been frustrated by a gadget, from trying to install a printer to spending hours setting up a new mobile phone. Page one of Simple and Usable points out that: “The Technology that is supposed to make our lives easier often feels like it’s on the march against us.” What then is the antidote to confusing products, software, and web sites? The answer is — as one might guess from the title of the book — simplicity. Simple and Usable is both an extremely approachable and an incredibly practical guide to simplicity. Author Giles Colborne compelling shares four fundamental strategies for accomplishing simplicity: remove, organize, hide, and displace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/09/27/review-simple-and-usable-by-giles-colborne.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/09/27/review-simple-and-usable-by-giles-colborne.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Paper &amp; Ink (Sketching Nutshell)</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;What does building a brand new CRM for medium-sized businesses look like? Way before pushing our first pixel, we listened to people recount their frustrations with CRMs on the market today. We had long discussions about how we wanted to both empower sales people to do their job more efficiently, and enable the business to control and codify the sales process. We spent long sessions in front of the whiteboard, and days sketching out and talking through these ideas. Now in the final stages of development (eying a launch later this year), we thought it as good a time as any to show you a few of those early sketches.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/08/26/paper-and-ink-sketching-nutshell.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/08/26/paper-and-ink-sketching-nutshell.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Designing the Search Experience</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/08/18/designing-the-search-experience.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/08/18/designing-the-search-experience.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Scent of Search</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;The implications of Information Foraging Theory on designing user-centred websites have not gone unnoticed. Jakob Nielsen and Jared Spool, among others, have put forth considered recommendations on how to enhance information scent on the web. Most of their guidelines, however, tend to assume that the designer has direct control over the explicit words used in the interface. While this is certainly the case for browse-based websites dependent on site-wide navigation and hyperlinks, it breaks down for search interfaces where both content and navigation are completely dynamic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/07/05/the-scent-of-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/07/05/the-scent-of-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Story for Complexity</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 30 Jun 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/06/30/the-story-for-complexity.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/06/30/the-story-for-complexity.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Concerning Fidelity in Design</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;People swear by their design process. Rachel Glaves insists on sketching by hand, Dan Brown urges extensive wireframing, and Ryan Singer goes straight to HTML. Conferences are filled with heated debates as advocates of each staunchly defend their favoured technique. With all of these different methods to choose from, should you be sketching, wireframing, mocking-up, or prototyping? The answer is simply: Yes, you should.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/06/29/concerning-fidelity-in-design.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/06/29/concerning-fidelity-in-design.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The Scent of Search</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/05/21/the-scent-of-search.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/05/21/the-scent-of-search.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A Bright New Future for CRM</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2010 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve been putting together a small slide deck explaining what’s wrong with customer relationship management (CRM) as we know it, and how Nutshell is getting it right. Fortunately for us, there’s a whole lot of room for improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/04/27/a-bright-new-future-for-crm.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/04/27/a-bright-new-future-for-crm.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>A History of Color</title>
				<pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/03/02/a-history-of-color.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/03/02/a-history-of-color.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Search Suggestions</title>
				<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;You used to be expected to type for yourself. But today people have come to expect a reasonable amount of help at even this task. Our phones now help us form correctly-spelled words, our browsers fill in long addresses after we’ve typed only a few characters, and search engines recommend searching for “Humphrey Bogart” after we’ve typed just “boga.” But not all as-you-type search suggests are created equal. Careful observation seems to reveal three different approaches: completion, suggestion, and instant results. These approaches range in cognitive burden on the one hand, and utility on the other. We’ll look at several examples of each and consider when they should be used.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/02/08/search-suggestions.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2010/02/08/search-suggestions.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Search Suggestions</title>
				<pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2010 00:00:00 PST</pubDate>
				<description>
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/02/04/search-suggestions.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/events/2010/02/04/search-suggestions.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>Minimizing Complexity</title>
				<pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2009 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Clean. Easy to use. User-friendly. Intuitive. This mantra is proclaimed by many but often gets lost in translation. The culprit: complexity. How one deals with complexity can make or break an application. A complex interface can disorient the user in a mild case and completely alienate them in an extreme case. But if you take measures first to reduce actual complexity and then to minimise perceived complexity, the user will be rewarded with a gratifying experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2009/10/07/minimizing-complexity.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2009/10/07/minimizing-complexity.html</guid>
			</item>
		
			<item>
				<title>The 1KB CSS Grid</title>
				<pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 00:00:00 PDT</pubDate>
				<description>&lt;p&gt;Other CSS frameworks try to do everything—grid system, style reset, basic typography, form styles. But complex systems are, well, complex. Looking for a simple, lightweight approach that doesn’t require a PhD? Meet The 1KB CSS Grid.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
				<link>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2009/05/29/the-1kb-css-grid.html</link>
				<guid>http://www.tylertate.com/blog/2009/05/29/the-1kb-css-grid.html</guid>
			</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>